<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-babe-ruth</id>
    <results>
      <result> 
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063381/1916-10-09/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1836&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Babe+BABE+Ruth+RUTH&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=5&state=&date2=1922&proxtext=babe+ruth&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=10</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>"BABE" RUTH PITCHES
              SECOND FOR BOSTON
              Babe Ruth.
              Babe Ruth, the Red Sox pitcher, is
              just about as valuable for his hit
              ting as for his pitching. Ruth has
              shown so much natural talent at bat
              that Bill Carrigan has seriously con
              sidered playing bim in the outfield
              when he isn't pitching
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1917-07-02/ed-1/seq-10/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Babe Ruth Is Lucky to Get Off So Easily After Hittimj Umpire
          FAR be It from ua to wish any guy haid luck, but It appears that Babo Ruth
          escftpefl too easily after his fight with Umplro Owens on tho ball field. Ban
          Johnson dismissed the matter with a flno of $100 nnd a suspension of ono week.
          This does not seem enough, nnd It Is certain that a player of less lmportanro
          would have been treated rather harshly. Ruth is one of tho stars of tho lcaguo .
          and a prolonged nbsenco would havo ruined Boston's pennant chances. Also tho
          gate receipts would have suffered. So Bnttllns Ban beenme as meek ns a lamb
          and decided to "give the boy another chance.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-09-06/ed-1/seq-11/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text> 
          Babe Ruth, the Winning Pitcher
          First Game in Figures
          BOSTON (American League)
          Batting Fielding
          ab r h 2b .lb hr tb sh sb bb ave. po a e ave.
          Hooper, r. f. 4010001000 .250 10 0 1.000
          Shean, 2b. 21 10001002 .500 0 .1 0 1.000
          Strunk, c. f. 1000000100 .000 2 0 0 1.000
          Whiteman, 1. f. 1020002000 .500 5 0 0 1.000
          Mclnnis, lb. 2 0 10 0 0 110 1 .500 10 0 0 1.000
          Scott, ss. 4 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 .000 0 3 0 1.000
          Thomas, 3b. 3 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 .000 i 1 0 1.000
          Agnew, c. 3 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 .000 5 0 0 1.000
          Ruth, p. 3 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 .000 0 1 0 1.000
          Totals.2S 15 0 0 0 5 2 0 3 .ISO 27 11 0 1.000
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-09-12/ed-1/seq-11/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ward somersiiult. While the crowd
cheerrd lie massaged his neck and then
'njitifri play Hut after' Pinch Hitter
r' Karrcll's hopes had flown skyward
"niii nian yielded his position to Babe
Ruth Tho fans stood and roared their
delight and appreciation as Whiteman
"I'ked to the bench, aching but happy.
' thn conclusion of the first Inning
- tentlemati stood in the press box and
".n-ed that for tho first time In
i.tstory of the w</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1919-09-25/ed-1/seq-16/#date1=09%2F24%2F1919&index=5&rows=20&searchType=advanced&language=&sequence=0&words=Babe+baseball+hit+Hit+Hits+hits+hitting+Home+home+Homer+Red+Reds+run+run%3FRuth+runs+Ruth+Sox&proxdistance=5&date2=9%2F31%2F1919&ortext=babe+george+herman+red+sox+home+run+homer+hit+baseball+&proxtext=&phrasetext=&andtext=ruth+&dateFilterType=range&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Babe Ruth Hits 28th Homer,
Ball Clearing Roof of Stand
Longest Drive Ever Seen Under Shadow of Coogan's
Bluff Ties Up Game in Ninth, but Yankees Come
Through With a Winning Counter in Thirteenth
By W. 0. McGeehan
Babe Ruth, of the Boston Red Sox, broke all home run records at
, the Polo Grounds in the ninth inning of the second game with the Yankees.
His twenty-eighth home run for tho season cleared the top of the right field
grandstand, the longest hit that was ever seen since the days when the
goats roamed Coogan's Bluff and even before that. Numerically it places
Ruth's home run record one beyond the twenty-seven achieved by Ed
Williamson in 1884.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1919-11-01/ed-1/seq-20/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Georsre Herman Ruth, better known as Battering Babe Ruth, prin
ipai slugger in major league baseball these day?, has recently given
ha world an insight into his peculiar brain procesa?if you will admit
e possesses a brain. Incidentally, hie speech shows him to be quite in
ccord with many others who think little of their plighted faith. Though
;? has two more years to complet? his contract ?with the Boston Red
ex at a salary of $10,000 yearly. Ruth would sign a new one calling
?7T $20,000 yearly. Furthermore, he says he will not play with the Boe
ra club unless his wishes are granted.
. Last spring Ruth held out until the last minute. He wanted a
alary of $15,000, if our memory be correct, but finally compromised by
?ft?ing a three-year-contract calling for a salary of $10,000 yearly. All
oat took place before he began hammering home runs until he had
Token ail previous big league records for this stunt. He admitted that
e was satisfied with the treatment given him by both Harry Frazee and
Jd Barrow. He proved it by playing fine ball all season. But Babe has
'?gtened to -erpent tongues. Now he would quit playing ball unless the
?oston club agrees to make a new contract calling for $20,000 a year.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1919-12-03/ed-1/seq-21/#date1=1836&sort=date&date2=1922&searchType=advanced&language=&sequence=0&index=10&words=Babe+Frazee+Red+Reds+Ruth+Sox+Yankees&proxdistance=5&state=&rows=20&ortext=&proxtext=babe+ruth&phrasetext=&andtext=frazee+red+sox+ruth+yankees&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=4</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Babe Ruth to Seek
Jack Dempsey's Crown
LOS ANGELES, Dec. 2. It was
announced to-day that Babo
Buth, home run record holder,
May become a professional boxer.
"Kid" McCoy, a former pugilist, and
Al St. John, a motion picture actor,
to-day entered into an agreement by
which McCoy will train Ruth for
thirty days and if his report was fa
vorable St John would finance a
campaign of the outfielder to obtain
a match with Jack Dempsey, heavy-,
woight champion.
Ruth has given up plans to become
a motion picture actor. Tho home
run champion satd ho used to be In
preliminary boxing contests In Bal
timore when ho was a mere boy.
"I always have wanted to be a pro
fessional boxer," said "Ruth to-night,
"but I gave up any future I might
have had in that game to play base
ball If McCoy and St. John think
I have any future, t am willing to
do everything they ask.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1920-01-06/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1836&sort=date&date2=1922&searchType=advanced&language=&sequence=0&index=6&words=BABE+Babe+Frazee+red+Red+RED+Ruth+RUTH+Sox+SOX+Yankee+YANKEE+YANKEES+Yankees&proxdistance=5&state=&rows=20&ortext=&proxtext=babe+ruth&phrasetext=&andtext=frazee+red+sox+ruth+yankees&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=5</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>BABE RUTH PURCHASED BY YANKEES FROM RED SOX FOR $125,000?OTHER SPORTj
Yankees Buy Babe Ruth
From Boston for $125,000
Manhattan Tribe Purchase Home Run Slug
ger From Hub City Team in Biggest Deal
In History of Baseball.
Boston, Jan. 5.?"Babe" Ruth, world champion home-run player
of the Red Sox, has been bought by the New York Yankees, ac
cording to an announcement made tonight. Harry H. Frazee, owner
of the Red Sox, who told of the sale of Ruth, declined to name the
price paid, but declared it was larger than had ever before been paid.
The deal was said to have involved no other players.
Estimates, unofficial, but said to have been based upon "inside
information," placed the figure at which "Babe" Ruth was told at
,the unprecedented sum of $125,000. Efforts to have this estimate
substantiated or denied failed, but it was generally reported that the
figure was not far from correct.
Highest Figure Yet Paid.
If the estimate proves accurate, the sale of Ruth not only ele
vates the trading of baseball players to inclusion in the category of
sugar, shoes, clothing and other high-priced necessities, but records
a sale at more than double the highest price heretofore paid for
a player.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045389/1920-07-18/ed-1/seq-49/#date1=1836&index=10&rows=20&words=Babe+Ruth&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1922&proxtext=babe+ruth&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>How "Babe" Ruth Grasps His Bat?and What Would Happen if a Gigantic Bat Were Swung Against a
Skyscraper With the Thousands
of Horse-Power Which All the
Home Runs Ruth Has Made Last ?.
The Story of One of "Babe" Rutli'o Home Runs Told in Terms of Science
A?The Ball as II Leave* tho Pitcher'* Hand, Rotating on Its Horizontal
Axis and Travelling at an Initial Velocity of 150 Feet a Second or
Nearly Two Miles a Minute.
B?The Centre of Percussion of "Babe" Ruth's Bat, Swung for One-Twen
tieth of a Second with n Force Equivalent to Forty-four Horse-Power,
' Meets the Oncoming Ball, Checks lis Course Toward the Catcher's
1 Waiting llnnds and Sends It Speeding at Greatly Increased Velocity
in mi Entirely Different Direction.
C?"I he Ball Immediately After Its Impact With the Bat, Moving Skyward
at an Angle of Forty-two Degrees and With an Initial
Velocity Estimated at Five Hundred Feet a Second
or Nearly Six Miles a Minute?Faster Than Any Ex
press Train Travels.
i D?Maximum Height Reached by the Ball as a Result
| of Its Collision With the Bat's
< Centre of Percussion, Backed Up
by Mr. Kuth's Forty-eight Horse
power Energy. The Height At
tained Will Be Greater on a Clear
Day Than on Ono When tho Air
Is Full of Moisture.
t,?Slowed Down by the Friction of the Air, the Force of Gravitation Begins to Overcome the Ball'* Initial
Velocity and It Stnrts Falling to Earth. Before the Full Effect of the Gravitational Force It Felt, How
ever, the Bull Mm 1 ravelled Far Beyond the Fielders' Reach and "Babe" Ruth Hat Scored Another Home Run
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1920-08-22/ed-1/seq-53/#date1=1836&index=1&rows=20&words=Babe+Ruth&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1922&proxtext=babe+ruth&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>"Did Babe Ruth Get Another One To-day?"
| Not "How Did the Game Come Out?"
*| Now the Great American Question 4
<
By W? O. McGeehan
IF THE lata lamented Shakes?
peare were a' baseball writer he
might usa a line that he
wested upon some more or less
obscure hero of antiquity and say of
"Babe" Ruth, "He doth bestride the
narrow baseball fields like a Colos?
sus." For "Babe" Ruth is Hercules
and Thor reincarnated, the Colossus
of Swat. His bat is the club of
Hercules and the hammer of Thor,
the symbol of sheer, primitive might
before which the puny folk bow and
offer worship.
But for the game of baseball, the
youngest game of the youngest peo?
ple, George Herman Ruth, the
"Babe" Ruth who dwarfs all other
personalities in the daily news,
might have been a peaceful cigar
maker or perhaps a third-rate
heavyweight pugilist instead of the
national idol of the American people.
The "Babe" was Fortune's dar?
ling, though Fortune concealed her
great and kindly intentions as far as
he was concerned when the "Babe"
was 2. boy. For the "Babe" was
born left-hander!. Hercules was a
right-hander. Thor never was pic?
tured as wielding his hammer from
the port side. None of the heroes of
antiquity, as far as can be ascer?
tained, was a southpaw. Harry Leon
Wilson was the first novelist to put a
left-hander in the near-hero class,
and he <i;d it in a half-hearted
fashion.
Moreover, little George Herman
Ruth was a half-orphan at a very
early age and was sent to an insti?
tution for orphans. He was nearly
an orphan boy, and, according to
the San ford and Merton books, he
should have taken a morbid sort of
point of view at an early age and
learned something useful. But the
youth of "Babe" Ruth was applied
mostly to the study of the great
American game of baseball.
You are not going to draw any
conventional moral from the early
boyhood of "Babe" Ruth. He was
not a particularly industrious or
thrifty lad, chockful of conventional
virtues. He was just a normal,
chuckle-headed combination of Tom
Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn. He
Was Just natural and just human.
FORTUNATELY the boyhood of
"Babe" Ruth was intrusted to
men who understand human
nature, and particularly the human
boy?the Christian Brothers, of Bal?
timore. The fraternity is not limited
to Baltimore. It is all over the
*orld. It is made up of big-hearted
?fcn. consecrated to the work of mak
lfig men out of the raw material.
They had charge of the bringing
UP of George Herman Ruth and
'hey have turned over to the world
??Colossus of Swat. It is due to
th*ir human understanding that
George Herman Ruth was not
wwarted and turned aside into more
Wo**ic iine8 0f encjeavor,
U?Kt lana&tiQ than ?sqr *rf fbe
I boy romances of Tattered Tom and
Ragged Dick, by Horatio Alger jr.
; is the rise of "Babe" Ruth. The Al-,
| ger heroes became mere bankers or
traction magnates, but George Her
| man Ruth, the waif of Baltimore, be?
came "Babe" Ruth, at whose shrine
' bankers and traction magnates burn
incense. Ever and anon these jaded
near-successes pick up the tape, not
to see the condition of the market,
but to learn whether the latest is the
forty-fifth or forty-sixth home run
! knocked out by the "Babe" for the
I season.
And these heroes envy "Babe"
! Ruth the left-handed, the boy who
! was regarded as far from bright in
;his classes. For the "Babe" can hit
them out with the joyous freedom of
Hei-culcs swinging his club or Thor
throwing his hammer through the'
clouds. All the tricks of the pitchers
are vain when he faces them, and all
the walls of the baseball parks are
lowered when his bat crashes against
the baseball. Homer would have
loved him if the blind singer had had
a season pass to the Polo Grounds.
THAT Ruth is the greatest bat?
ter of them all is admitted by
two members of the old Orioles;
and when two members of the old
Orioles agree upon anything, that
makes it official and irrefutable. If
there is anybody so ignorant of im?
portant American history that he
does not know who the old Orioles
are, we will explain, more in pity
than in indignation, that the old
Orioles were members of the great?
est baseball team of a generation or
so ago.
The two Orioles who made the ad?
mission that "Babe" Ruth was the
greatest baseball player in the whole
world are Wilbert Robinson, mana?
ger of the Brooklyn National League
baseball team, and Joseph Kelly,
scout for the Yankees. Both of these
gentlemen are grandfathers and citi?
zens of high repute in the city where
they dwell, which also happens to i
be the home of "Babe" Ruth. "Wil-1
bert Robinson was a catcher, and still
; holds the world's record for consecu?
tive base hits in one game. Joseph
Kelly was an outfielder of sorts on
the old Orioles, and his present oc-1
cupation is "ivory hunting," looking
upon baseball playera and appraising
them ?at their true > jrtb to their
employers and to the national pas?
time.
These two authorities admitted" to
me in th? presence of witnesses that
never, even in the days of the old
Orioles, was there a baseball player
who could hit like "Babe" Ruth. Con?
sider the importance of this admis?
sion. The members of the old Ori?
oles are the most conservative per?
sons in th vorld. Never before
have they au. : ..ed that any player
of the present was anywhere near as
wonderful as tl\e players of their
glorious day.
"He can hit them harder than any?
body, and he can hit them oftener,"
they admitted from the fullness of
their hearts. They did not qualify
the statement, They did ?ob assert
that the pitchers were less canny
and that the ball parks were smaller.
They admitted that the heroes of
their day were lost in the shadow of
the Colossus of Swat. They admitted
that even in the days when the old
Orioles were young "Babe" Ruth
would have loomed up above them
all.
That Ruth broke all big league
records for home run getting last
year is in the book. That he has
broken his own record this year and
is on the way to setting a mark far
beyond the misty horizons ?if the
baseball world is l?o\vn. But the
old Orioles have explained away the
performances of other more modern
heroes of baseball. Ruth's achieve?
ments they Jr&ott ungrudgingly.,
That is almost as marvelous as the
achievements themselves.
.
ONCE upon a time the youth of
this land worshiped another
young giant, a right-hander
and an exponent of another and el?
der sport?John L. Sullivan. The
right arm of John L. ?Sullivan was
mighty in its day, but the left arm i
of "Babe" Ruth is mightier in its I
day and generation in the matter of
sheer numbers of worshipers.
| They used to block the corridors
of the hotels, and even the streets,1
? to see the mighty John L. pass. They
do that in the case of "Babe" Ruth,
I too. It is not for me to disparage
| the memory of John L. Sullivan, the
| gladiator, in th? days-cf hi? greatest
-?
ring glory, but I think, that his ad?
mirers saw that particular John L.
through rose glasses and that they
worshiped an illusion.
The John L. Sullivan of the later !
day, the John L. who beat down his ?
own worst enemy and lifted up his ;
self-respect from the muck, was the
John L. that should have been wor- ;
shiped, for that John L. Sullivan :
was a mighty gladiator. The John ,
L. Sullivan who knocked out ring an- j
tagonists with a right-hand punch to j
the jaw was a mere mass of brawn ?
and muscle, but the gray and fat old |
John L. who conquered himself was i
the true fighter.
But we are considering the John L.
that was the popular idol, the '
brawny man who was followed by '
the men and the boys and cheered
when he stalked abroad. He was !
not a particularly affable character.
This big "Babe" Ruth is a far
more likable person. He is full of i
good nature and the joy of living.
He is a modest enough young man, :
and he knows his limitations, though ;
he acknowledges no limitations as j
far as the baseball diamonds and j
the fences around them are con
cerned. He is not falsely modest to
the point of affectation, for he has
that supreme confidence in himself
that comes after certain achievement.
But he will not play to the gallery
consciously. He likes the gallery
and he understands it, and he likes
to have it understand him. ?
Ruth is, perhaps, too simple, or
it may be too wise, to try to fool his
gallery, as other stars of his own ;
game or stars in other lines of en?
deavor have tried to do in vain. For
nobody can fool his gallery. No
truly wise man ever tried.
THE best judges of a man ar?
the men with whom he works !
or with whom he plays.
"Babe" Ruth, naturally, is the high?
est salaried ballplayer on the New
York Yankees. He might, if he were
like some of the stars of baseball or i
stars of some of the arts, claim all
the privileges of a star and hold
himself aloof from his fellow players.
Here again is the simplicity or the
wisdom of "Babe" Ruth. He plays
the game with the team and for the
team, and the men ' he plays with
know it and appreciate it. "Babe'
Ruth will even make the "college
try" to get a base on an impossible
chance. The "cdllege try" is the vet?
eran professional's term of contempt
for zealous endeavor that seems fu?
tile on the facts of it.
_ an the "Babe" *nake?th? two
owners of the Yankees, Colonels I
Ruppert and Huston, shudder with !
apprehension when he hurls himself
against a wall to get a fly ball, or I
when he throws his huge bulk
through the air in the effort to steal i
a base. They rejoice in his spirit
and his wholehearted way of play?
ing, but at the same time they per?
spire with apprehension lest some?
thing should happen that would de?
prive them of the most expensive in?
vestment in professional baseball.
Some stars have disrupted base?
ball teams, rousing jealousies, but
"Babe" Ruth, admittedly the great?
est star of them all, has made the
Yankees a team. The advent of the
"Babe" has brought them the chance
of that "world's scries dough," which
should be something like $7,000 a
player. It has also made them the
team of the big leagues. They do not
begrudge the "Babe" the homage
that is paid him. As far as Ruth
is concerned, there is no professional
jealousy on the Yankee team.
Just to what extent the present
prosperity of professional baseball
is due to "Babe" Ruth I would not
care to say, but it is considerable
When I first trailed West with tht
Yankees, they told me in Chicagc
that there had been little or no in
tereat in the Chicago White Sox. Bu
I when the Yankees came ta Cbicagi
they turned out to the extent of 20,
000 a day and upward to see the
"Babe" "bust one."
Once, with the score 2 to 1 in the
eighth and a tense pitchers' duelen,
the Chicago pitcher passed "Babe"
Ruth. Ten thousand people started
to walk out of Comiskey Park.
There remained yet the chance of
the melodramatic ninth inning rally,
but the ten thousand had lost all
interest in the game for the after?
noon. It was clear thatr they were
not going to see "Babe" Ruth knock
a home run, and nothing else mat?
tered.
Civic pride, inter-city rivalry, in?
terest in the national game were
minor considerations. The "Babe"
was not due to "bust one."
IN CLEVELAND 1 was talking
to two tired business men early
in the afternoon.
Said one of them gravely:
"This 'Babe' Ruth is a menace. He
is responsible to a large degree for
i the lack of production in these
: manufacturing towns around the
Lakes. Go out to the ball park to?
day and you will see thousands of
young men taking the afternoon off
just to see 'Babe' Ruth 'bust one.'
i It is really quite serious. What are</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1921-06-15/ed-1/seq-19/#date1=1836&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=BABE+Babe+Ruth+RUTH&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=19&state=&date2=1922&proxtext=babe+ruth&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=10</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THutJ Babe , Blurted In yesterday by
mslrin thelon(;-dlstanco home run
matku-ho hiulvaet the day before by
cloatliitf the tltlrd ball George Datum
pltahed him In .the third Inning over
theijht centra Held bleachers fence
fornoi dlstanco of 450 feet, a truly
trcmendouM w.iOup and said to be the
longest hit eves uiadu In major league
Ttrcro la no mistake about trtio lljf
urosr'Hcnry FabVm, groundktepcr of
thol?olo Grounds, jind 1 measured It
after-' the tramo, accompanied by
another reporter.
Tle blow, which was the sncund
homo run the Habe had made otf
DauA during the game', cleared tho
fence about twenty fuet to the lutt
of his hit of Monday, -which went
ilirectly over the Tanglefoot Hlgn
through the bleachers' exit ut that
point.
nenry Fabian's tape iiieaanro shows
It Is 432 feet 3 Inches from home
plae to the point where Monday's hit
cleaved. The ball then loll to tho
trottlid at a distance ten feet rfroni tho
tenv line a total of 442 feet 3
Inches, over all.
yesterday's blow, however,, hud to
travel 433 fret before It cleared tho
fervce,. becausu thu Inclosuro curves
ouUut'rdly and tho auglu of tile arc
biKeutd by the ball Is U feci 'J Indies
further from homo plute.
Muo.. the ball remained In tho air
it reached the fourth row of
leariher seats, whence It fell like .1
plummet to the clndors underneath.
cxaotly fifteen feet from thu fence
linn, a- total of 450 feet from the borne
pl.ittiM.iid nearly eight feut longer than
his '.longest" hit of Monday.
I'olo Grounds ami no other
majir, Jeague Held havo a hit to equal
It iu'Uingth. Geoi-go Kelly's clout over
the.le.rt Held bleachers wall, lluua
Wagner's even longer mash about
fifteen feet to tho right of 'hat and
McujqJ's hit Into the left centre iloid
bleachers are conceded by those who
saw these hits made, although they
wcr'Sever measured, to havo been
shoMer. Meusel's was perhaps the;
lonuvKt of the three1, approaching
Babe's, hit of Monday for thu record
bet Ay him then.
However, long afl the Babe's hit was.
nncflf probably will be a mark for
n miters. Including the Babe hlm-
!;hcU, to shoot at for a long ttmo, It -Is
inot, according to Henry Kublaii, tno
jongCBt bit evor made.
Henry has statistics In h's memory
from which ho exhumed yaslerday
the- records of a hit made by one Ed
Cartwrlght In tho year 1488 at Naw
Orleans. Cartwrlght, said Henry, hit
.for EuO feet off Pitcher ueorgo Wash
ingtun Bradley of Savannah, whose
,namo ls sufllcleut to make tho story
true.
But, In achlltlon to the length of
thM blow, tho day was otherwise full
on glory for George Herman. It was,
,uUia3 been said, the second homemin
ho .had got during tho game. It was
thin fourth ho had got In two days and
tho day's clouting made the fifth
day in succession that he bad knocked
out homers. ' Ho started last Fri
day against Bagioy of Cleveland. Ho
!hlti another Saturday off Mlddleton of
tho Tigers, another Sunday off Suth
erland and then two Monday off
Ehvnke and two yesterday off Dalies
dewen altogether In live days, to
Hay -.nothing of hitting four in succes
sion. A.1bV It was bis twenty-third four
base U'ow of the season, and tho 126th
of his .major league career, exceeding
tho liftVlme big league record of Cac
tus CrtAyath by five. And tho Babe
still a comparative youngster!
Incidentally, the Yankees made it, by
the score- of 9 to 6, a clean sweep,
four in a ran', off Ty Cobb's Tigers.
Ty, who had been In somewhat of
an eclipse, slammed a homer across
In the sixth 'Oft Rip Collins, but there
was no one on a base, while Roger
Pocklupaugh was on each tltno the
Babe hit his.
How Babe Ruth Surpassed Own
World's Home Run Record Here
After slamming his two homers In
tho llrst two times at bat, the Babe
In tho fifth swung mightily but glanc
Ingly, and grounded weokly to Dauss,
making an easy out at first.
Frank Baker also Ml a home run In
the seventh with both Ruth and I'ipp
on bases.
HOME PLATE '
MAmm "
BABE RUTH'S HOMERUN
RECORD NUMBERS 23.
lid be natli milled two niorr horn
run to Ilia 1HUI crop nt thr I'olo
Ground jrrttmtsy wlicn he alnmmtd
thr Imll Into thr Irft flrld blrachrn
In I lie flrxt limine nml Into the erntre
flrld blcurlitri In the itTrnth. Tho
Ilrttxi now hnt nunle irrrn clrrnll
miiihra In tli litt file imrl nnd Ida
totul for (tie urnvon la "it.
Ilr nrtsla US more to pttM the mnrk
he rttnullshed Innt rnr. Tho chnncea
lire In furor of III bentlnc till own
rrrorcl, for the Ynnka have 100 (niet
to itn7
Until mnde ld tnrntjr-KMond home
run In lltU otf I'nmock nt the I'olo
Grounds on Juno 'M nud hU twenty
third off lllbi nt PhllnJr IphU on
June 110. lie I Id dayn alicnd of hU
taut jrur' rrrortl. lie now hm m
ininil total of I'M home rniu to hU
eredlt.
DIAGRAM SHOWS DISTANCE OF BABE RUTH'S
RECORD HOME RUN HITS ON MONDAY AND TUESDAY.
I Baker was saved an error in the
i sixth by a magnificent throw by Blpp.
Frank had overthrown first In his
, haste to throw out HAlmann, but I'ipp
I retrieved the ball from right field and
I threw out Hollmann to Ward at
I second.
Aaron started oik: of tho snappiest,
double plays of many a day In the sec
ond by scooping 1 1 fuu'a ho groundor
find beating Hellmann to second In
time to throw out the Tiger first
baseman at first.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042243/1922-03-15/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1836&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=BABE+Babe+Ruth&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=19&state=&date2=1922&proxtext=babe+ruth&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=6</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>"BABE" RIJTH'S SALARY
"Babe Ruth," baseball star, is to receive a
salary of seventy-five thousand dollars this year,
with an additional five hundred dollars for every
home run he bats out. On the basis of his last
season's record this should bring his income for
the coming eight, months' work up to well over the
hundred thousand dollar mark.
To many this will seem arf^rtjtf^Sbe. Thej^-will
point out the fact that the President of the United
States draws only seventy-five thousand dollars a
year that the Secretary of State gets but twelve
jthousand that the salaries of most of our gover
in&rs and college'presidents average around ten
thousand dollars a year. These are vocations that
require years of training, of research, and the
hardest kind of work.
Yet, along comes a baseball swatter with no
special intelligence, and gobbles up a salary great-: h^f^I VutyT
er than that attached to the greatest office in the
land.
Critics of "Babe" Ruth's salary should not for­
get that thley are living in America. This is a
j.free land and it offers opportunity for advance
jment to every citizen. What better proof is need­
ed than these very facts albout "Babe" Ruth. An
orphan, with no parents to guide his steps and yet
with all his handicaps he is raised to the seats of
the mighty,' with a salary that exceeds those of
the mighty.
It cannot be luck. Ruth 'has specialized. He
has trained. He has made himself the ibaseball
swat king of America. His name is known from
coast to coast. His admirers are legion.
America cannot cry down the salary "Babe"
Ruth gets. His work is measured by his follow­
ers, and it is the people who indirectly pay him.
He is the best in his field. America offers sim­
ilar opportunities in every line to every citizen,
and should not be afraid to boast of it. As Emer­
son so aptly put it a generation ago:
"If you can make a better mousetrap than your
neighbor, the world will make a beaten pathway
to your door."—Minneapolis Journal,
t....</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1922-05-26/ed-1/seq-18/#date1=1836&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Babe+BABE+Ruth+RUTH&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=19&state=&date2=1922&proxtext=babe+ruth&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>BABE RUTH LIKELY TO DRAW PENALTY FOR EFFORT TO PROTECT HIMSELF
WASHINGTON TIMES SPORTS
FRIDAY, MAY 26, 1922.
F
Suspension Likely for Ruth,
But Incident Draws Attention
to Fans' Cowardice.
By lolls A. HOLGHKR.
Babe Ruth is likely to he pun
ished severely for entering the
grandstand at the Polo Grounds,
New York, and seeking to ham
mer an insulting fan. There are
two sides to every question and
the ball player has an excellent
argument to offer in partial pal
liation of his offense.
Ban Johnson is expected to sus
pend the Yankees' home-run hit
ter for ten days. He may impose
a heavy fine on the player. But
Ban Johnson will do the game a
great good if he will investigate
conditions surrounding the inci
dent at the Polo Grounds.
It Is admitted that Babe Ruth
ov?rratepped the hounds on the play
ing field when, called out stretching
his single, he tossed a handful of
dirt at Umpire Hildebrand. He wps |
ejected from the game for that, then ?
and there.
It is admitted that Ruth commiited
a cardinal offense when he lef< the I
playing field and sought to beat up |
one of his insulters. He is vet to.
be punished for that.
Nevertheless\ Bah* Rulli and |
every other player In ihe ma.ntr
leagues is entitled io prole? limi
from insult and injury on the par!
of the public. It is all tnirutivrnt
for a club owner to say he cannot
stop the Rood of villifi? at ion such
as we heard shouted at Rulli yes
terday snd Wednesday.
?
Babe Ruth is a young man. He ?
la lio better anil no worse ih.in any
?ther man.
Babe Ruth, because he can hit I
home runs, has been raised on a
pinnacle extending wcllnigh lo tho ?
skies. If it has turned his h?ed. |
there ia good reason.
Babe Ruth, be? atise he has not *
been hitting home runs in every !
game since his return to the New
Tork lineup, ha? been the tarnet ;
for Insults shocking to one not ac- I
customed to them</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-charlie-chaplin</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-11-04/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>PASTORS CANT COMPETE WITH
CHARLEY CHAPLIN
Milwaukee, Nov. 4. "Charlie
Chaplin" sermons were called "im
possible" by the Rev. Samuel H.
Woodrow of St Louis in speaking be
fore the Woman's Board of Missions
of the Interior, which closed here to
day. "There has been much talk about
making sermons interesting," said
the speaker. "We never can make
sermons as interesting as melo
dramas or prayer meetings as amus
ing as Charlie Chaplin. They never
were meant to be so.
"If a heathen dropped into New
York and saw a church with a seating
capacity of 1,500, attended by about
200 on Sunday and dark six days a
week, he would never go back with
the impression that the United States
was a Christian nation."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085187/1916-03-10/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Charlie Chaplin is going
to get $87 0,000 this year for
making a fool of himself.
And just think of the num
ber of would-be ball tossers
who do the same thing for
nothing every training sea
son.RIVALRY BETWEEN MOVIE MEN
Charlie Chaplin, highest paid
actor in the world, is appearing
at the Melbourne and Liberty to
day in the same picture, "His
First Vacation.'' Never before
has the same actor appeared in
the same picture at two Tacoma
movies at the same time.
It is an evidence of the keen
rivalry between movie men. The
Melbourne had signed the film
for next week. The Liberty, how
ever, obtained the same picture
for the latter half of this week.
Manager Sumni**rville of the Mel
bourne telegraphed a hurry-up
order for his film yesterday when
he heard of the Libertys' move,
and obtained his copy of tlie film
by express yesterday. He put it
on his bill at 4 p. ni. without an-
Tlie picture remains at both
houses until tomorrow night.
CHAPLIN AT
LIBERTY
The old favrolte — Charlie
Chaplin—who has returned to
the IJberty.
Movie fans who see Charlie
Chaplin this week at the Liberty
will not only see the world's
greatest comedian in action, after
a long vacation, but will witness
the work of a man who gets
$670,000 a year for being foolish.
Chaplin recently signed with Mu
tual at this price. His Liberty
film, "His First Vacation," is
added to the regular bill of "The
Innocence of Ruth,' a clever
;crook drama.
BABY FILMS
AT COLONIAL
In view of tlie fact that Ta
coma Is, at the present time, in
terested in better babies and an
observance is being held here for
three days beginning today, it
is an opportune time to mention
the excellent and instructive film
shown at the Colonial theater
every week on better babies. The
films are ln the form of a series
! WHERE TACOMA IS
| AMUSING ITSELF
Theaters
; .TACOKIA
[ Next Sunday and Monday—
; "Peg o' My HeHrt," with Flor-;
' ence Martin nn "I'eg."
KMl'ltliSS
! "The Girl In the Taxi," by
l Wilkes players. Matinee But
; nrday, next welt, "Inside the
; Lines."
PANTAGES
Ward's five piano girls, nnd
> good vaudeville acta.
Movies
APOLLO
"The Eternal City," Froh
; man feature photoplay, with
t Pauline Frederick.
COLONIAL
"Tennessee's Pardner," with
I Fanny Ward, \
M KLHOUHNE !
"Via Wlreles," with Galli
1 Kane and Bruce MrKae, and J
: "Hlii First Vacation," with r
■ Charlie Chaplin. \
LIIIRHTY [
"The Imnocence of Itut!i."<
with Viola Dana, and "Hi-
Flmt VacaUon," with Chafici
Friday. March 10,1916,,
Charlie Chaplin lias tlie honor
of appearing at two bin Pacific
avenue photoplay houses today
and tomorrow in the MUM pic
ture—a feat never before accom
plished in Tacoma by any motion
picture actor.
and fully show the best care that
can be given to infants. Tha
methods shown have been en
dorsed by the best known physi
cians of the country. The bath
ing, dressing, feeding snd .gener
al care are illustrated with tha
statistics given on the screen.
These pictures are shown every
Sunday, Monday and Tuesday.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87093407/1916-04-22/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>IN NOON PARADE
Charlie Chaplin* Give Down
town Seattle Lunch
time Laugh
THEY'RE LED BY BAND
The downtown aection of
Seattle waa all messed up with
Charlla Chapllna Saturday
noon.
About 300 boys, all coatum
ad Ilka Charlie and Imitating
I th* ecrean comedian'a famous
walk, participated In Tha
Star*a Charlie Chaplin parada.
Tom North, Northweat minuir
of tfc* film led '*•
profession la his automobile Then
nm» Cavana'itha band, and then
the rarortlnn Chaplin*
Other automohllrs brouaht up
the rear, one of them rirrylii* the
Judaea
Th»re were Chaplin* of all a»e*
and aires, from boya of 5 rlear up
the line.
f'rlrea were awarded at Iton
March* park, at the conclusion of
the parade
N'orman Hsrkett. leidln* man
i for Wlike* player* at th«> Metro
! i>olHan. Mavor'a Secretary Jlmmv
I 'rehan. li. S Tolila*. of the North
ern Pacific, Tom North and John
liamrli'k were Judaea
Klrat prlite *'»* $25 In ca*h.
given by INmrlck. who I* man
ager of the It**. where Chaplin'*
burleaque on "Carman" I* now br
ine shown Second prl»e wa* a
125 watch. glv»n by Tom North
Third prlte wan a 125 *ult of
clothe*. given by Channcey Wright.
Other prlaea of Rei pa**ea were
given
Ttio i!»t of prlre winner* will b*
anrmnn'ln Monday'* Star
The only red-beaded Charlie
Chaplin In the world *i» dlacov
ered In thr parade
ll« had clipped a wlap of hi*
own brick-colored tre**e* and paet
ed them on hla upper lip.
During the performance at the
Hon Marehe park, one future
oon a year comedian lost hla baggy
trouaera while doing the Charlie
Chaplin walk</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014682/1917-10-15/ed-2/seq-5/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Phone 5701
Charlie Chaplin the real one may
remain in Honolulu for a short time,
but Charlie Chaplin the reel one is
almost a permanent fixture. Provided
the management of the Hawaii thea
ter can s'o arrange, C. C. will be a
perpetual attraction.
There is little difference with C. C.
as to the title of his attractions. Just
so long as the leading comedian of
the screen is in the billing Honolulu
and every other city in the world will
turn out almost en masse. i ne cur
rent Chaplin attraction at the Hawaii
happens to be entitled "The foreman,"
and the title is a good one as it is
an excuse for Chaplin himself to ap- j
near for a couple of reels of laugh J
production. As is customary with
Chaplin's films there is nothing to it -
but laughter, although that commo
dity is more plentiful than at any time
at the Hawaii since, the last appear
ance of the same star. '
Lillian GIsh also appears as a .Ha
waii star in. "An Innocent MagdeleneV.
a strong rnangie-r me ah imiuic
This Is one of the Hawaii favorites. ;
g
fti nuA An QHn
nuuiinf iniwut vMiwwi
CHARLIE CHAPLIN, AND
SAILS AWAY FOR HIL0
Boyishly beaming with satisfaction
at the great crowd present, Charlie
Chaplin reeled up the gangway or the
Mauna Kea Saturday afternoon before
departing for his visit to the volcano.
Minus his makeup, "moustache.
i ,
cane ana massive snoes, some ui
the many children present could not
be convinced that their screen idol
had really come to life in Honolulu
until the comedian twisted his ears,
wrinkled his face and let his feet per
form. Then there was a chorus of
childish voices shouting, "bee Char
Hot"
lib
Cliarlie had scarcely boarded the
steamer until lfe and Demosthenes
Lycurgus had established an entente
and posed with arms locked for a
squad of amateur photographers. Due
to "Monty's" plentiful proiwrtions
there was grave danger of the Vol
cano hotel manager "hogging the
camera," until Charlie was placed on
the weather, or camera, side.
As the Mauna Kea pulled into thqi
stream, the screen comedian waved
a red bouquet, tiped his white flan
nel hat, shuffled three dance step3,
did a" donkey" with his cars, smiled
his Roosevelt smile, teeth and all,
and shouted "Aloha kakou."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058246/1917-11-15/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CHARLIE CHAPLIN
IN HAWAII
HONOLULU, Nov. 12. Tho fam
ous Charllo Chaplin arrived in Hon
olulu, October 10, and whllo ho in
tended to como for a rest betweon
custard pio throwing contests, ho
waa'kept cxtromely busy sightseeing.
Photographers camped on his trail
and snapped him riding tho sivf
boards on tho Beach at Wnlkl, eat
ing two fingered pol, dancing with
tho hula girls and even flirting with
Polo, tho Goddess of Fire, on the
odgo of tho Volcano at Kllauoa.
It Is expected that ns soon as his
contracts permit ho will bring over
a company and bo filmod with an
Hawaiian setting which will bo uni
que. Ho was accompanied by Itobort
Wagner, tho well known writer and
they returned to tho mainland, Oc
tober 17, tired, but happy.
Charlie Chaplin, movlo king, small
boys loud his praises sing. Ho will
bo back with us today from a trip
to Hllo bay hero ho went to visit
Pelo and to see tho lnva Jolly. Char
llo likes Hawaii's stylo and ho fain
would stay awhllo, loafing on tho
sun kissed sand, eating pol with
cither hand; Hstonlng to tho ukuolo
played by Walkikl, 13111 Dalloy; oat
Ing.dog in guiso of pig; practising
thb hula Jig. Dut no's got to get
back home and with us may" no
moro roam back to make a nation
smile In raro Charlie Chaplin's way.
When his pictures come this way
as they will on some flno day, wo
shall watch for something new In
the moving scenic vlow. Wo shall
hope His Nibs to see In tho surf at
Walkikl, look to see him gaily prance
in tho featlvo hula dance, and find
Joy without alloy, in tho palo elus
ivo pol, Charlie Chaplin's back to
day. Hip hurray! Banzai! Hurray!
We shall seo him, I've a hunch at
the merry Ad Club's lunch, where
ho'll pick a friendly bone and make
Jokes to help tho Loan.
Now, togethor, small boys all old
boys, bold boys, short or tall, when
the boat pulls out tomorrow show
your very earnest sorrow that C Q.
has got to go, that .,tho parting is
a blow, by parading to tho boat there
to take a final gloat at tho moving
picture king; hark, the herald angels
sing!</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-05-12/ed-1/seq-37/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Capturing Charlie Chaplin
By Harriette Underhill
Once upon a time we did not love
Charlie Chaplin. It was not so long
ago, either?not more than two years?
and it was when all movie houses re?
leasing his pictures had those horrible
wooden effigies of him in the lobby.
This may have helped to prejudice us.
At any rate, we used to glory in the
story of the nice old lady who went tim?
idly up to the box office and said: "Ex?
cuse me, "but is Charlie Chaplin's pict?
ure showing here?" "Yes, ?madam," re?
plied the box office man. "Going on at
2 o'clock." "Thank you," replies the
n. o. 1. "Then I won't go in." We al?
ways quoted that nice old lady and
never felt that we were really under?
stood unless we could find some one to
talk to who didn't like Charlie, either.
This was not so difficult at first, but
we felt that we were rapidly losing our
very best supporters, and hardly a day
passed but some one of them went over
to the pro-Charlies. Then along came
Heywood Broun, "our favorite dramatic
critic," saying that Charlie Chaplin was
screamingly funny and an artist. We
began to weaken.
First we went to see a Chaplin pict?
ure with an unbiassed mind. Then we
went to see another one voluntarily,
and then we fell to wondering how long
we must wait for the next to be re?
leased.
Four days ago we saw Charlie Chap?
lin talking to a man in front of Clar
idge'8, and we became incoherent with
excitement. It was the first time we
ever had seen him off the screen, and
we were immediately stricken with in
terviewitis. Stage and screen persons
have come to be merely subjects. They
are good, bad or indifferent?mostly in?
different?but Charlie was a prize not
to bo ignored.
The fact that he was avoiding pub?
licity and had refused to see all inter?
viewers made the thing so much more
interesting. The most he could do
would be to deny his identity and say:
"Madam, how daro you! I am not that
sort of person." But fortunately his
countenance was not as inscrutable as
that of the hotel clerk up at the Ritz,
where Charlie has his modest little
three rooms and five baths. But more
of that hotel clerk later.
At any rate, we decided to sacrifice
everything on the altar of duty, so we
went straight up to the great and only
Charles and just as we were about to
pluck him by the sleeve and say, "Ex?
cuse me, Mr. Chaplin, I'm the person
who has been writing such nice things
about you," we discovered ?hat the
man he. was talking to was the man
who writes the second best movie re?
views in town.
Of course, even with a proper intro?
duction it was a bit disconcerting ?to
meet your screen idol so suddenly,
without his shoes or his cane or his
hat, and yet we knew him immediately.
Wo apologized for the interruption,
mentally deciding that wild horses
couldn't drag us away until we had had
a chance to find out just how Charlie
Chaplin talked, how he thought, how
he dressed and how he looked.
He talks humorously, he thinks se?
riously, he dresses quietly and he
looks handsome. He has the whitest
teeth we ever saw, the bluest eyes and
the blackest eyelashes. "How did you
know me?" inquired Mr. Chaplin
naively. "Why, you look just like your
pictures," wo answered truthfully.
"Not my pictures on the screen, I
hope?" said Charlie. "Oh, no," said
we. "But, you know, occasionally one
does see a photograph of you in a
magazine." "Oh, I see," said Charlie.
"Such is fame." And then we said
pleadingly, "Won't you please let us
interview you?" To which he replied:
"You know, I haven't seen a person
nor talked to any one, but if you'll
promise not to say anything about my
work for the government, why?all
right."
He looked terribly suspicious. Just
as though we were not taking more of
a chance than he was. Hadn't we seen
him drop ice cream down a lady's neck
and get her involved in a revolving
door and trip her up with his cane?
And how could we tell what moment
he might pull a dog out of his. trousers
pocket or drop an egg out of his hat on
our new suit?
But he told us that he never again
would pull a dog out of his trousers
pocket, because Mutt, who co-starred
with his master in "A Dog's Life," is
dead, and no other ever shall take his
place. When Charlie came East he
left Mutt behind, and to, being only a
dog, Mutt refused to forget his beloved
friend. He starved himself to death
and was buried on the 29th of April.
"Every one told Mutt that I would
Burely return, but perhaps he didn't
understand, or perhaps he didr?'t be?
lieve them. At any rate, he never would
] eat after the last time I fed him, and
the inscription on his tombston^ reads:
'Mutt, died April 29?a broken heart.'"
We talked to Mr. Chaplin for an
hour, and then he suddenly remem?
bered that he had to go out and make
a speech on the subject which we
promised not to mention. And he told
us about how much better he likes the
West than he does the East, and ad?
mitted that he could play the 'cello
and the violin and the piano, and thst
he had worked for two-and-six a week
in London, and that he didn't know
why people laughed at him, and how
he first walked his famous walk. The
other things which we learned about
Chaplin are probably known to every
one who knows Charlie.
A Haven at Last
"I can't tell yo?a how wonderful it
seems to be taken care of at last. I
never knew that I was a clinging vine,
but I.guess I am, for now all my worry
is over, and I sha'n't have to look out
for myself any more. I can relax and !
rest on my oars."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1918-11-12/ed-1/seq-13/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Charlie Chaplin Married;
Bride a Movie Star of 17
i" 1 i
4 V
MILDRED
WARRIS U-
CHAPUN tfc".'.,
WITHHOLDING AERO CLUB
PRIZE REPORT DENIED
Awaiting Official. Notice of Winner
In Statue of Liberty Flight, Says
Officer of Organization.
Th 9 report, published In one New
York paper, that tho Aero Club of
America had held' up prises Which It
offered for tho winner of the race from
Helmont Park around tho Statue of
Liberty on the ground that It would
r.ft be lecmljr to present the guerdons
to a non-commissioned officer Is dented
by Alan It, Hawley, rrctldcnt of tho
club,
"The story Is made out of whole
cloth," ald Hawley to-day. "The Aero
Club Is waiting only for (ho proper of
ficial notincntlon os to who Is the win
ner. It la generally understood that
Beret Clnrcnco Coombs won the race
In record time, but tho club has re
ceived no omclat report to that effect.
We bare not the slightest trace of feel
ing against Eergt. Coombsv On the
Contrary, we have as a club entertained
him, and stand ( ready to deliver the
priio to him as soon as he Is officially
declared the winner.
TUGBOAT MEN AT WORK.
nesntne Job After Olbrtlort Fol
lorrlnK Knd of Strike.
Striking lighter and tugboat men who
called oft their strike yesterday but
postponed going back to work until
after they had celebrated aermanya
surrender were on the Job to-day.
Danger of a freight embargo probably
has been averted. It was stated at the
office of W. 1J. Pollock, Federal Director
of ruilroai Marino freight In New
York.
SAGE TEA TURNS
GRAY HAIR DARK
Wedded in Los Angeles Oct.
33 Official Carelessly
Reveals Secret.
"When I wanted to marry I didn't
have tho money. Now thut I havo
tb.3 money, I don't care to marry."
Theffo wcrt) once Charles Spencer
Chaplin's sentiments, but elnco ho
mado that remark tho same Mr.
Chaplin, who Is Charilo .Chaplin,
Charlie of tho films, tho llttlo fellow
who lias made millions laugh at Ills
queer shoes and ridiculous mustache,
and, Incidentally, has mado millions
of. dollars for himself, lias been in
ducted Into the ranks of tho bene
dicts by charming Miss Mildred J
Harris, another screen star, of Loa
Angeles.
Tho woolnff under a bunch of
"Coopers" Instead of a moon was
all kept very secret, and his most
intimate friends were as surprised
as any one else when tho news was
mado public recently that Charlie
and Mildred had slipped quietly away
to th houso of R. S. Sparks, head
of tho Loa Angeles County Llcensa
Bureau, and had been married by
the Rev. James L Meyers,,
Tills all happened ns far back as
Oct S3, but they successfully kept the
newo to themselves until recently Mr.
Sparks let tho cat out of tho bag when '
he laughingly remarked that Charilo J
would liavo to work overtlmo now!
that ho had a wlfo to support. When
questioned further Mr. Sparks con
firmed tho story of the marrlago and
added:
"Mr. Chaplin did not want any c.v. .
awiuciu muuo over me mamaga. no
told mo that unless It could bo kept
very quiet ho would go to soma other
county seat for a license. It would
never havo dono to let Charilo Chup
lln go to any other placo than Los
Angeles, so I did my best to keep
things as quiet as possible."
Tho girl bride, for .Miss Harris Is
only seventeen years old, has the
ability to throw an appealing, chnrm
Into her picture, work, and Will bo re.
membcred by movlo .fans for this
quality In "Tho llrldo of tho South,"
in which aho appeared. '
Charles Chaplin was born In Lon
don in 1830, and Ills first appearance
on tho stage was with' his parents
when ho was eight years old in "Krotn
Itags to ltlclios," which tnust have
been an omen of gooll luck, for tho
last pari of tho title of that llr.it play
has certainly como truo with lilra. ,
DR. FERNALD, AUTHOR, DIES.
Ho Wrote St Ilonk on Knllli I.n-
KiiilKr nml IMItril Dictionary</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1920-08-29/ed-1/seq-29/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Charlie Chaplin in a Care-Free, Gay S
having Just the Way He Did Not,
Says, So Far as She Was Conce
NO recent case of broken romance and
once fond hearts estranged has created
such Interest as the suit for
y divorce by Mrs. Charlie Chaplin against
her husband, the world famous funny man
of the motion pictures. The charges
i brought by Mrs. Chaplin are "mental cruelty"
and failure of her husband to provide
for her. /
Among the millions whom Charlie Chaplin
has made laugh there l'"ve probably
been msnv. wl'o hove thou?V*. how carefree
and amusing the lot of the woman
vas his wire. No wcma'.i, It would
could ever have the toluss or be
'ig but cheerful with so m.rthi~
a companion. Yet strangely
rre are no sadder, more posai'?
than the professional humorni
to use up all their store of
* n ;r output. And, according to
"u. Charlie Chnnlln w.13 no exI?
?>. ?ho t?lls What she alleges
1 it di1' story of her life with the
.! 11 on earth?so far as the
< r >uo?rncd.
1 ir.ilin has denied all that Mrs.
^ charges in her suit, and has ex
d bhn elf as being much surprised
r d cslon to force the Issue. He will,
i jai,:, bring counter suit against her on
j _vanccr of his own, and Incidentally al
ges that, despite her charge of penury,-
lie spent over 160,000 In about eighteen
months in housekeeping expenses, although
during that time Mrs. Chaplin herself
was earning $1,000 a week.
By Mr*. Charlie Chaplin</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1920-12-19/ed-1/seq-36/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Charlie Chaplin in CI
I T was n odd match when the news
leaked out that Charlie Chaplin, fun
niest comedian in the motion picture
world, had married Mildred llarris whose
film specialty is tears, "sob stuff." And
the news of the marriage 'was soon follow
ed by whispers that the funny man bride
groom was not getting on very well with
the tearful bride.
Nobody seemed to know jti~t what was
the matter but in due time Mrs. Chaplin
admitted that she and her husband had
separated. Then followed several state
ments from Mrs. C'haplin but no comments
came ifom Mr. Chaplin.
At last the 'matrimonial troubles drifted
into the Los Angeles courts. Mrs. (Chap
Iun brought suit for divorce. And here on
this page is the sworn testimony given by
Mildred liarris Chaplin in support of her
plea for a divorce. Mr. Chaplin did, not
tak9 the trouble to appear at the trial and
Ch lie (Chaplin's version of the matter is
not on record.
W~hen the case was called recently be
fore Judge York Mrs. Chaplin took the
..uness stand in her own behalf. Ii.
tt
IoyMod
boy efMouscoedan
DIRECT EXAMINATION.
QUESTION BY LAWYER GILBERT.
State your namd in full, please.
ANSWER BlY MRS. MILDRED HARRIS
CHIAPLN-Mildred Harris Chaplin.
QU'ESTION.-How old are you, Mrs.
Chaplin?
ANSWER-Nineteen.
Q.-How long have you been living in
California?
A.---Since I wgs seven years old.
Q.-When were you married?
A.-October 23, 1918.
Q.--When did you and Mr. Chaplin be
come separated, finally?
,A.-A year ago this comigg February.
Q.-Were there any children by this
marriage?
A-One boy.
Q.-ls it living or dead?'
A.-Dfead.
(Q -You say you were married when you
j ,.. s.eneen years of ae?
fred Harris's Si
that time
A.-My other
Q.-idsh kep oucostatl4ude
her cre?
A. - hed .
Q-twstecureo odc
whc ormte urudtwr o n
had a teahe for me
Q.-Wht ha bente gnraod
tio ofyu.hat veic, hte
wasdnot ver srong whenI wS marr
Q.--u mn byChaplouhaenee
A.-Yes.
Q.-tutimrs teamn twr
A.-Mey moteetadr ey.oey
Q.-How ohd keep yo. Cnhapnt uthe
tihe arr d ou
Q.-You aege ourse coanuta
whicthe yourstero pfurse toard yofter
yoawre argryand yarraeduatkep
an mterst. A twhoae kugetinnastht
A-Mor. Chadawanen'mst
Q.-Dliad hated io ny meason fiur.
whn accoun twlv proesoldrao and te
her areacohe for nom areo.el e
Q.-Yout aeen your comgena ad
fiour ofks you heaheve sie. whithspl
ofv lnever bnter riblypr stron. aut el
thae hadr abu fe thelaotl. esbt ee
veryserous foutridek, of perhaet fever.le
was, notery wetwrn mared I was arre.
Q.-Dyou go? ythtyuhaebe
A.-Yes.
Q.-Yuu t hern ,te mrrag became
A -Veryseta.vr oey
irprising Stor3
e Famous Fihn
R4
LMOST
flattered
wife of
could sle hope i
pects--such a ric
fagnous husband
And such fun i
dian around the'
half a dollar or :
for half an hou
his fun making,
have him all to I
Think of it!
To be the bri
man in the worlk
ing till night, to
his stunts in her
Would he hoo
ankle with that
squash pie in hei
the door on h
friends wondere
to-be was sure I
the rough stuff
little wife. Of c
id
Charlie.
Q.--Now. after the marriage becam4
public. Mrs. Chaplin, just tell the court ii
~nur own way about the course of treat.
ment Mr. Chaplin adopted toward yoi
after that time?
A.--Well, after I was taken out of thi
hospital I had to stay in bed until Christ
mas, Christmas Eve, and the doctor sent
a nurse home with me, and Msr. Chaplli
got us a home up in 4,aughlin Park, and
lad (po stay in bed until Christmas Eve
and that was the first tim9 I was dowil
after I got out of the hospital. .And
(Christmas afternoon-! mean the day be
fore Christmas, Mr. Chaplin told me that
he would be home and have dinner with
me and help me trim the Christmnas tree,
and I had had mother get all the Christ.
man presents. I was not able to get ui
and I had always thought a great deal of
Chirstmas, and- that evening. I dressed and
went downstairs and waited for him, and
hIe did( not come home. And I waited until
11 o'clock. and he did not come, so I trim.
med the tree and mother helped me and
then I went to bed and stayed awake unti
about two or tlpree, and Mr.' Chaplin came
hiome about three o'clock.
Q.--What occurred?
A --And when he came home he came
utpstairs and was very angry at me for
b'uyirig so many Christmasapresents and
making~ such a time lover Christmas.
Q.-Then what occurred?
A-Then the next day was C'hristmam
D~ay, and he would '?ot get up all Christmna'
morning, and I went downstairs and took
him uip his presents and he was very angry
at me for making so much over Christmas.
Q.-What would he say? What did hi
bay?
A.--Well, he said it was very foolish
and that he did not believe in such thing'
and that I should not be so silly over
C'hristmas and over having presents and
liking such things.
Q.-Now, then, you allege that after that
Christmas evening he began a course of
conduct toward you of absenting himmell
frum home. Tell the court about that.
A-In February the doctor said I had to
go up to Mt. I owe for my health. I kepi
of Her Domes
Comedian WI
scent Divorce
iford from Mr.
on His Side of
ny young woman would be Harris a
to be invited to become the Last Oct
Charlie Chaplin. Where twenty-i
o find more attractive pros- The a
;h, amiable, entertaining and Judge 7
as he was certain to be? story of
to have this inimitable come- part of I
house! If it was well wortl; divorce.
nore to sit in a tleatre chair lin woul,
-and watch "photographs of. of a br
what would it be worth to after th
terself all the time? What a
Charlie
de of the merriest, funniest Christn
1! All day long, from morn- Some zi
have Charlie Chaplin doing And i
6wn home. -but th
k her around the neck or her ed that
busy cane of his, or land a own woi
face at dinner time, or slam testimo
er fingers? Miss Harris's low on I
d about that, biut the bride. s Unfer
he comedian would cut out was not
at home and with his own made hil
ourse he would I So Mildred it to the
getting wors And worse and I couldn't
eat, so the doctor sent me up to' Mt. Lowe.
Q.-Ygu were in bad shape physically at
that time, as I understand,it?
A.-Yes, sir.
Q.-9go ahead.
A-l went to Mt. Lowe and Mr. Chaplin
ould not ith =' e said he had to
g aw I*= aWd 11d to be away from
me, for a while. I beWd him to go with
me, ,but he would not go, so he went to
Coronado.
Q.-With whom?
A.- th 18 secretary, and stayed down
there a fiew "ye.
Q-Abo three weeks, you say?
A.-Ae stayed a few days, and then he
came back to his house. I could not stand
it say longer. so I went down to the city
to ask hib if he would come up with me
to Mt. Lowe for one day, and he said he
would not came.
, Q.-Ne said he would not come?
A.-Tes. So I took quite ill and threat
mend to do everything In the world If he
would not come up with me one day, so
he went up with me for one day and said
he had to go right down; that he could
just stay that day.
Q.-He got up there at what time in the
morning?
A.-He went up in the evening and he
went down the next morning.
Q.-Then how long before you saw him
the next time?
A.-Then he went back to Coronado.
Q.-Well, how long did he remain there?
A-He stayed a couple of weeks.
Q.-Were you Ill all the time you were
at Mt. Lowe?
A.-Yes.
Q.-Who was with you?
A.-Mother was with me.
Q.-Now, on this Qhristmas evening you
have told about, the first Christmas even
Ing after your marriage In October, you
had invited your friends there to the
house, had you?
A.-No, I had not; Mr. Chaplin bad all
his own friend.; he did not want me to
have mine.
,Q.-Then, you allege, that he came home
about what time on Christmas morning?
A-It was about two-thirty or three.
Q.-Two-thirty or three. Then nal
Christmas morning what occurred?
A-He stayed in bed all day until four
o'clock; he wouldn't go down stairs with
me to pee the tree. I took him his
presents.
Q.-Did he abuse you?
A-He was very angry at me for mak
ing so much over Christmas
Q.-What did he say?
A-He said It was very foolish an,1
wasn't right to make so much or for me
to like presents and foolish thing.; that
it was not his idea to have Christmas or
celebrate Christmas; he had never done It.
Q.-You allege in your complaint that
you had always had girl friends of ap
proximately your own age as companions?
A-Yes, sir.
Q.-What condition existed after you
were parried with reference to whether
or no~ he would permit your tiends to
come and visit you?
A-He did not like them: he didn't
think that I should see them; he thought
I should like hi. frend. and be more
studious.
Q.-What did he say or do with refer'
once to your friends V he should find them
in his house or the house, what was his
conduct toward them?
A-He was uot nice to them; he
wouldn't come home if I bad them.
Q.-When you had your frends he would
refuse to come to the house if he found It
out?
A.-Ya., air.
tic Life.
ich Won Her
but Not a
0
Chpin
It AU
-ried him. If was two years. ago
s. She was seveuseen, he was
nas.
ther day, in a Los Angeles court,
rk listened to Mrs. Chaplin's sworn
how the great comedlian.played the
sband-and gave Mrs. Chaplin her
It was expected that Charlie Chap
I be a very original and unusual sort
degrom. He was. Two months
ey were married Christmas came.
Drt of frolic would you imaginl
Chaplin would think up for hig
a celebration with his young bride?
we1y, some surprise of course.
was an entirely unexpected surpried
s unique way the comedian celebrat
Christmas is told in Mrs. Chaplin's
1 as given in the transcript of the
y at her divorce trial printed be.
his page.
sately, Charlie Chaplin himself
present in court to explain what
n play the part as his wife described
judge.
Q.-Haw oftea did that occur, Mrs.
Chaplin?
A.-All the time; he would never tell me
when he would be home; he said he had to
be free to live his own life and do as he
plealed.
Q.-Now, on that Christmas did he give
you any present or token of any kind?
A.-No.
Q.-Was he earning money in consider
able amount at that time?
A.-Yes, sir.
Q.-He made you no present whatever?
A.-No, sir.
Q.-What was your condition at that
time of your trip to Mt. Lowe?
A.-I was expecting to be a mother.
Q.-And he knew that?
A.-Yes, sir.
Q.-At that time did you have a contract
with the Universal Film pompany for your
services?
A.-I did.
Q.-Tell the court about that with refer
cnce to his insisting on your working when
you were unable to work?
A.-Well, when we %rere married Mr.
Chaplin told me he wanted me to break
the contract with the Pniversal, because
he did not want me iorking with them.
So, when I was in the hbspital, after I was
first taken ill, I sent a written notice that
I would not be with them any more and I
was under age. My lawyer told me we
could break the contract. Then, in Feb
ruary. when I came back from Mt. Lowe.
they had been sendjag me my check each
-:eek, and I had been sending them back
and they would return them again, but I
had not cashed any. In February a friend
of mine, Miss Bweet, asked me to go to
New York with her when I came back
from Mt. Lowe, and Mr. Chaplin had been
away so long, and when he came back he
said it would do me good to go to New
York, so I wentt with her. But he wouldn't
give me but $150.'and when I got East r
bought a lot of baby clothes ad some baby
furniture and a few other things, and I did
not have enough money and I wired for
more money. But he would not send me
any more, so I wired mother to please
ash one of my checks.
Q.--That 'was the check that would re
a-dirm your contract irith the Universal
-eople, which he advised you to break?
A-Yes, sir.
Q.-Did you advise him with reference
to your circumstances?
A-Yes.
Q.-DId you advise him that you expect
ed to purchase some furniture for the ex
pected child?
A-Yes, sir.
Q.-And he declined to send you any
money at all?
A.-Yes.
Q.-And he was making apozimately
16,000 or I7,000 a month at that time?
A.-More than that.
Q.-You mentioned the furniture. You
say there was an arrangement made about
snme turniture for the baby's room?
A.-BDefore I went East Mr. Chaplin said
Icould get a set of furniture for my room
un in our home, because it was very dark.
Q.-That was the room in which you
were to be confined?
A.-Yes, sir; my own roem. So. ?
hoght it at Beriker Crothers, end when !
got back from he . York the room was all
=urnished in thE aew furniture, ad he
took me up to see it, and I was very happy
about it aid he seemed to be quite pleased.
but when the bfll came he refused to pay
it. He said it was too expeasive and tat
Ishould send it back.
Q--Did you send It back?
A.-No, sir.
Q.-What did you de?
(Oontinseed on Neat Pugf)</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1921-08-31/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Charlie Chaplin Proclaims
In the Matrimonial Market Again
In 3-Minute Hot Weather Interview
HQ' l:LXvs Irf '5
Comedian Strategically Shy on
Most Questions, but Vents
Some Positive Opinions
Doesn't Know What Sort of
Woman He Likes Best and
Would .Rather Read Hamlet
Than Play It.
By Mar giteriteMooersMar shall
Charlie Chaplin, tho playboy of the
movies, Charlie of the funny feet, the
trained mustache, the Incredible head
gear, handles ,a three-minute Inter
view with all the care he does NOT
bestow on oustard pics and cops.
Charlie is ever so polite about it, mit
nevertheless he acts as It he thought
The Evening World's hot weather
test In mental speed were a bomb of
some sort that might go off in his
hands.
When I saw the brown-eyed, debo
nair, soft-voiced little comedian in the
theatre lobby Just after the rehearsal
of the next release of his friend Mary
Pickford and Just before the showing
of the newest picture of his friend
Douglas Fairbanks, he leaned against
the wall for support, wiggled his fin-
gers nervously and took his full three tatlon. although you'd think him quail
minutes to nnswer the fifteen qucs- fled to answer this one) Make them
Hons I had prepared.
.
viwot TiTirrTP
rjiioj juinvj u,
Gains on Schedule, but Parries Most
Thrusts.
It was exactly 17 minutes past 1
when I asked:
Q. No. 1 What Is It that makes you
so funny?
Charlie Chaplin (grinning bashfully.
60 that he showed most of his very
hlto and even teeth, and looking orr
into space, somewhere over my left
shoulder) I don't know ask tho kids.
Q. No. 2 Ought movie salaries to
go down?
Charlie Chaplin (straightening his
drooping shoulders, an Indignant In
flection In the soft voice) Certainly
not!
Q. No 3 Is the Rolshevlk Govern
ment going to last In Russia?
Charlie Chaplin I do not know.
Q. No. 4 Why don't you want to
marry again?
Charlie Chaplin (who was recently
quoted as saying that he didn't, but
who seoms to have changed his mind
girls, here's your chance!) Who
says that I don't? Quoting me to that
effect was a ralBtafce. I certainly do
want to marry again very much!
Q. No. 5 What sort of woman do
you like best?
Charlie Chaplin (again grinning em.
barrasscdly and tying his fingers Into
bowknots) Now, that's hard to an
swer; I really couldn't say; I couldn't
even tell whether she's blond or bru
nette; I couldn't answer that.
Q. No. 6 Are you In favor of an
Irish republic?
Charlie Chaplin (determinedly play
ing safe) I prefer to be discreet and
not commltmyself.
The first minute was gone and we
were one answer ahead of the avcrago
called for by the tlmo schedule.
SECOND MINUTE.
Slows Down His Ansuers, but UoUls
to Schedule.
Q. No. 7 Should women smoke
cigarettes?
Charlie Chaplin (hesitating, Hps
moving nervously, then smiling dlplo-
vicw to obtaining an Increase In
fares. Nathan Kushncr, No. 1057
Simpson Street, former Interborough
guard, said that while there was no
official union statement showing that
the company was back of the strike.
It was freely passed from one em
ployee to another that tho company
was going bankrupt and that the
only chance for employees to get a
pay increase was to help tho company
obtain a ten-cont fare which tho
company would share.
Commissioner Hirsuficld said that
the Interborough receivership move
In designed to got an Increased fare.
Tho Transit Commission, ho said,
fears to gTant an Incrcaso for political
reasons. If tho company gots a
"friendly receiver, ns in tho cose of
the D. It. T.," ho predicted, "It will
separate its elevated and subway
systoms, doing away wlln transfers,
and thus getting the equivalent of a
I fare increase,"
MAKEi VOU FUNHV ?
SHOULD
i AUAt?l C.S GO DOWN r"
i-v-"rwe. QqusHcvik govt.
WHV DONT YOU 'wAKl-r
WOMH bQVQU
LI KB. OE5T ?
DO YOITC.VOR.
WOMEN SfrvlOKC
oovoo itsm-icvi;
wm,t qovoo
DOWITW YOUR
MOM JCV ?
OOV T HEtPTHC
ON EMPI.OVCD?
wi-wr isthc
EVSICtTr WAV
"TO MAKE PEODLE
IAU&H ? it'YOO
JVCRENOT, A. MCVIC
SfAtfc WHAT WOULD
Vvuix-r i - w-.. r: .
THE VOISTKAOIAW,
PIES HAVf
VOU WUINtD IN -YOOCL
CAREER -p
matloully) That depends
woman!
Q. No. 8 Do you believe In national
censorship of the movies? m
Charlie Chaplin (repeating the
question to gain tlmo and thinking
hard) Do I believe In national cen
sorship? Yesif It's intelligent.
Q. No. 9 Whit do you do with all
your money?
Charlie Chaplin (tho hundred candle-power
grin again turned on) Pay
my taxes and spend some now and
then.
Q. No. 10 What should the Govern
ment do to help the unemployed?
Charlie Chaplin (who takes a de
cidedly sorious, non-facellous Interest
in labor and social problems) They
should do a great dcal-so much that
I couldn't begin to cover the subject
een if I todk the whole time you
allow for tho Interview.
Tho second minute was up, and we
had lost our one-answer lead owing
to the comedian's habit of stopping to
think before he spoke.
THIRD MINUTE.
Finishes Exactly on Time and Seems
Glad It's Ocer.
Q. No. 11 What is the easiest way
to make people laugh?
Charlie Chaplin (with modest hesl-
nappy. I guess uui someutxiy eiso
could answer that question a good
de-'11 better than 1.
Q. No. 12 If you weie not a movie
star, what would you like to be?
Charlie Chaplin (with a quiet
chuckle) Night watchman.
Q. No. 13 Hqw many custard pies
have you ruined since tho beginning
of your career a million?
Charlie Chaplin Oh, not as many
as that. Say a. thousand!
Q. No. 14 What is your
opinion of the Volstead act?
Charlie Chaplin (the laugh
candid
In
ins
eyes, as well as on his lips, and look
ing me straight In the face for almost
' the first time during the Interview)
Of the Volstead act? You must ex
cuse me I don't use such language!
Q. No. 15 When ate you going to
play Hamlet?
Charlie Chaplin 'although this role
is said to bo his dearest ambition)
I'd rather read It. What I really want
in my future work is to do as I please
to follow my own whim!
The interview and the three minutes
were over. Charlie seemed glad the
bomb had not exploded!</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024827/1921-10-02/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>BY CHARLIE CHAPLIN
LONDON, Oct. 1. I always figure
America under the symbol of youth
vigorous, aggressive, full of hope and
pen. courageous, and with the sun
light of the morning shining in its
eyes.
I find England more like a serene
old age mellowed by time, softened
ly suffering, wise from long experi
ence and with the. afterglow of the
westering sun in its eyes.
America, like all youth, has a core
of hardness in its heart.
England, like all mellowed old age
has a core of tenderness in its heart.
I should say America for work,
England for thoughtful contempla
tion and dreams. ,
Of course, I know England is one of
the mightiest nations in the world;
that its hardy sons rule an empire;
that they sail all seas and traffic In
all markets. But I am merely trying
to give my own impressions, to tell
how the two countries 'affect me.
I don't think I could do much work
in England. Everything Is so finish
ed, so settled, so restful that it would
simply absorb' me.
America Is Restless
nut there Is in America a feeling of
the unfinished, of restlessness that
ius. makes one want to get up and do
thjngs. That is why I am going back
In a few weeks.
It's all very nice to say that Chap
lin brings laughter to men, but the
truth is that Chaplin is working for
his bread and cheese just like the
rest of you. There is not much fun
jn loafing too long.
' I have been rediscovering England
for myself aiyl contrasting my Im
pressions of America and also with
my memeories of the England I knew
as a boy.
' I came to America when I was 18
und In the past 14 years have only
been back home once. .
My best experience has been to ram
ble around the streets in the poor
sections of London that I 'used
know. I found in the mean streets
something very lovely, something spir
itunl. I nian as regards the people.
There they were, living in misera
ble ( tenements, their faces thin and
pinehed from poor food, and yet there
w something very beautiful in their
eye.
I. have never seen anything sweeter
than the expression in the face of a
girl out walking with her coster Tcrer.
I began to understand how these
poor people had suffered during the
long years of the war and how thev
had found the pluck to do it. and 1
saw the mak rit had left on them. It
was saddening as well as beautiful to
get these -revelations.
Had "Emotional Jag"
Then I had an emotional jag. I
prowled these poor streets in search
or a wistful little bov I used to know
a little, ill-dressed, rather fright
ened Charlie Chaplin.
Somehow. I couldn't quite catch up
with him. The streets all seemed nar
rower to me than they did to that
little chap, and the crowds not quite
so big and bustling, and the policemen
not quite so terrifying.
1
N
I
. it I
-3- Vy :
i
, ' "ft:
4 V;
CHARLIE CHAPLIN . ,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1922-04-16/ed-1/seq-61/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Charlie Chaplin; the Man
By Everett Dean Martin
Social Psychologist, Director Cooper Union Forum of the People's
Institute, and d of "The Behavior of Crowd$."
_ ??Te \pro.\p r\y Charlie Chaplin.
>ffv ?,;;,,. b) Harper * Bret %
' \ i THINK ove: te Chaplin
,% en, it strikes
^Ja that the essential ele
X -* ment in them is not the
thrown m the dice or the clown
tics. I dent believe that these
is? Ivea would have
Charlie his almost universal
"^ai In hi? autobiographical book.
;8,t published, "My Trip Abroad." there
rj revealed another quality which, on
?-.l'.ysis is the thing that constitutes
?pea! on the screen. There's a
human Sympathy coupled with a
umor, and this humor
. after ? :. ?". psychological compensa
?on for something which lies much
?fcpt
1 . yov.-, here is the thing - Charlie
lim ' ,n uniforT,l!y aPP??r? on the
;? .e?n as a vagabond adventurer. Hes
Byway? on the outside looking in. n
? ?eotly figure, undignified, ridiculous,
;3 a world rires?=cd tin and formal. This
garla is presented partly as a joke on
hm, ar.d in the end the situation is
reversed and the joke is on the eonsti- j
tated order of things. In every one of
i .5 there is this hidden scamp hero with
whom Chaplin identifies himself and
with whom the world of respectabilities
??nd conventionalities is in conflict.
Chaplin expresses for us an imaginary
escape from this conflict and he does
it by resolving it into a joke.
? ? a
rpHERE are people who are suffering !
asid lonely and defeated who save ?
their ?elf-feel ng with just this sort of
homer directed at themselves. The
profotindtst humor in this world al?
ways has a touch of the pathos of a
man^i struggle with his r:te. The es
tablir-hod ord - of things forced on
us all rcmaii tact. Chaplin doesn't
ap?it ? order of things,
? f ; idiculous he> ?g
aSi? at tief- same time to preserve thai
Mtablisl and kei p alive that
in hin -? ??; v hicli is in con
Sict with?? by making it, aiso. ridicu
[oqI. B that kind is what
psych i fi nee mechan
iim. It show! that with all our obeli
ID? md conformit/1 to established
imething in us which
is in this world but not of it. Chaplin
bowl this secret and reveals it in
Iiiis hook.
Gar!... Chaplins book is from the
psychological angle a remarkable hu?
man document, greatly because of this
revelation. It explains the appeal of
this poor little feeble creature on the
outglde of the great big world. To the
reade?r unversed in psychology the
outstanding features of the book are
likely to be the triumphant return of
Charlie Chaplin to the land of his birth
his meetings with the great in poli?
tics and letters his sympathy for the
unfortunate his intimate confessions
of his likes and dislikes. However, the
real revelation lies in Charlies visits
to the haunts of his childhood.
Trio whole tone of the book is that
of a half lonely ?dventurer visiting the
scene:; of his early 1 i fr. reacting with
genuine sympathy to every situation.
We learn of Chaplins early experi?
ence as a little ragged urchin. On top
of that, experience has been imposed
this magical thing- for his succ?s?? has
been like an Arabian Nights fantasy?
and 1 doubt if he has ever quite real?
ized tha ?t vvas he who has had it.
This little ragged urchin has stayed
v.ith Chaplin all his life and is the
main reason for his tremendous hu?
man appeal.
? ? ?
OUR or five years ago ?ome neigh?
bor child came rushing to me, all
out of breath. She was all excited, for
she was going to the Hippodrome to see
Charlie Chaplin himself. ?
At thar time Charlie Chaplin him-
self didnt mean any more to me than !
Charlie in the, movies. But after read?
ing his book T feel that I do know
Charlie Chaplin himself. In another
age. where he would have had to ap
pear directly in person before his
audiences, the chances are that the
personal side of his art would have
been more evident to the people, who
are rather inclined to look down on
the movies, anyhow, and who have re?
garded Charlie Chaplin merely as a
comedian who makes lots of money.
The motion picture ,is a medium of
expression is a syndicate sort of thing.
It takes a tremendous amount of per
sonality to overcame the? difficulties
 !. ? crowds who have bcen rooting for
Chaplin have been psychologically cor
rect. While he has an enormous popu
larity, he doesnt make an appeal to
the crowd mind, but rather a secret
h stance to civilization which is in us
nil. and he does it because at heart he
is really the littlo ragged urjhinthe
vagabond adventurer.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024827/1922-09-17/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CHARLIE CHAPLIN? RUMOR SAYS
LILA LEE TO WED COMEDIAN
EM
- " -
- ' -
TO
FULFILLTREATV,
DECLARES
Air Over Orient Is Rapidly
Clearing, Says Secretary
of Navy on Return
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 1C. How
do the Oriental political skies seem
to the eyes of the secretary of the
navy?
Edwin Denby, back from a wide sur
vey made unofficially but neverthe
less thoroughly, says he "is convinced
that the Japanese will sincerely ful
fill all obligations of the four power
treaty." He talked freely and frankly
"And naval disarmament there?"
he was asked?"
"Japan has not yet scrapped a
ship," replied the secretary. "But
neither have we. There is nothing
threatening about that. It is not to
be expected that any guns will b
spiked until the treaty has been rat
ified all around. Our navy will not
(Continned on Page Two)
LILA LEE (CENTER), PEGGY JOYCE (LOWER LEFT) AND CHAR
LIE CHAPLIN- '
LOS ANGELES, Sept. 16. Will
Lila Le be the next Mrs. Charlie
Chaplin?
This . question is frequent 'in
Hollywood following announce
ment by Mildred Harris, former
wife of the world famous film
comedidh. that such was the ru
mor amongst those "in the know"
in filmland.
Among those who have nothing
to say about the rumors are
Charlie and Lila Lee.
The former Mrs. Chaplin, in
telling of the Lila Lee-Charlie
Chaplin reports, took occasion to
announce that Peggy .Joyce, for
merly speculated upon as the fut
ure Mrs. Chaplin, was no longer
considered as a possible bride for
Charlie</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-harry-houdini</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1906-01-07/ed-1/seq-43/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>And Houdini does doesnot doesnot doe doenot s
not seemed to be affected by the notorlety no notoriety notoriety ¬
toriety he has achieved He is quite quitemodest quitemodest quit quitmodest e
modest and unaffected unaffectedYou unaffectedYou unaffectedYou
You would give the police p policetough mce a atough atough
tough time > if you tenould turn crim criminal crimInal trimanal ¬
inal I observed j
withdanger smileis thoreIs stackof stackIs
of police admissions r to t defeat der t t at at the thehands tho thE thEI theI
Is no danger 1 make all the money moneyI
hands of Houdini After all it does doesseam dUfsThe duess
I want honestly honestlyThe honesU It
if the sleuths are are not as a av s in invincible inthe inthe ¬
The secret of yoa yoar oa power lies in inthe seam Qom as
the th authors of tenccutthe tencent tencentliterature tencentmost
vincible incible inaiblomost as
the fact that you OU are probably tho thomost v
literature literature would have havens vc believeRSE believe believePRANK believedoes
most expert locksmith in the world worlddoes tibelieve
FRANKPractically FRANK T M0 MORSE MORSEVENPALL MORSEPractically ti RSE
does it Itnot not I inquired inquiredPractically
Practically yes os I lean can open the theordinary VENFALL VENPALLCome VENFALLordina VENFALLCoflfe
Come heap the leg logtl le + and > iM4 the tht > blaze biazoup hlaz hlazUP blazeordinary
ordinary ordina r handcuff by y simply rap rapping ¬ up higher higherAnd hIgherping
And mjike good gooay cheer h he l r ab about ° t Cta roaring roaringnre roanngthe roa yin yinfire 1 1ping
ping it on the floor I understand understandthe mll fire nreNay
Nay N ay butI butthe but the thethink bluebirds s h heret rei Or OrI stay stayI gt gtthe tiY tiYI tiYlmow
the mechanism so thoroughly that I Iknow I I think thinkI
of the thf > bobolink bobolinkatxtp HJJ Unk UnkWas
I heard the laiUtUing
know just how to it
tap to make it itfly
1 ttk ttkfly to k kfly
Was I that Ole ash b upon a
fly open For such easy tricks I Idont atxtp atxtpOr INlp INlpdont +
Or Is t the blue bloom of a a pulpy pulpyffr pulp1oa pulpsdont
dont mind allowing a II ovo f ng the spectators spectatorsto ffr grape grapeto gapetiKithhi n nWithin
Within my chimney ch imney corners cornersgleam orner happy happygl halpye happyto
to watch me It is when wh e n I have havesomething h a e gleamcloud gl gleam gl6llU11something un unA
A > cloud of wlsard sprites the seasons seasonssosm aeasonsa eeasonssomething
something very difficult to perform performthat
seem sosmAnd a seemAnil 8J1l 8J1lthat
that I retire into my Ghost House Houseto And nIl al U the year ye ear + a manycolored many + utored dreamQ dream dreamCan
to Q prerreerre preserve prierve my secret secretDo Can I mistake or was t yesterevo yesterevoI yestrevoDo
I saw th the fireflies dance the fairiesDo fairies fairiesweave fairlsu
Do Do you u meet mee meet t many people who whosee weave weaveWas woavesee weaveWas
Was It this morn that from his sphere sphereof spherAof
see it ail ailOh ai a ° of flame flameLove flameOh flameLove
Love stooped delflc uttering lt tllS my nam name < 7 7Surely 1ere
Oh yes in every every audience There ThereIs Th ere Surely Surelyno no music mur ie or of flute or orbtrd orbtrdis bird birdLike birdL1kO
Like Ljko the childs voice this afternoon afternoonI
Is always some some one to cry fake But Butthere
I hoard hoardThrough h hoardThrough rd rdthera
there Is no fake about It It f l can canopen Through what meridians of light you youtare ou ouopen
tareOh tare
open open locks thats all allI Oh lovely IIf life and through what stress stressyou stressI stressyou
you ou bear bearMy bearos bearI
I ros rose r os to t 0 go with genuine regret regretHoudini My Iy wondering soul to this ftNner + r ratter < mer airl airlHarriot air airHoudini atriHarriot
Harriot Prescott Pr a Ott Spooffiurd Spoott rd in Con Ccatury Contur
Houdini is an entertaining talker tury tur</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1906-09-29/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>TO HOLD HOLDHOUDiNI HOLDHOUDiNIMter HOUDINI HOUDINIAlter
After flftyaeven minutes confinement confinementIn
t f In a zinclped imcaped box prepared prepared by em employe employ employes ¬
ploye ploy of the William Knabe Kn1be Piano PianoCompany PtanoCompany PlaneCompany
Company Harry Houdini Jail breaker breakerand breakerand breakerand
and indcuff iidcuff king kln who wa waaUeci was tied band handamljt band1H1 band4i
amljt 4i 1H1 1 to a chair with a rope rop before beforeentering beforefntetn beforeentertn
entering fntetn the case reappeared rea ed on the tbestage thelitage theatae
stage at Chases Chaae last night J just 6n the thestroke thetroke thettroke
stroke troke of midnight midnightlioudioi mldnltrhtHoud101 midnightIloudlot
lioudioi went Into tbe box wearing an anImmaculate an1mmaculate anImmaculate
Immaculate stiff Uff shirt high h collar and anda
a wellpressed evening suit When he hev hewas hewas
v was as next seen hi his collar and tie were weremissing weret wererising
missing t i 5iDg hi hlB hiashirt shirt was wringing wet his histruuscr h hI hisI hisruU5era
I truuscr stuck to him and his h l face faceeh facebhOWCd
I eh bhOWCd owed wtCI plainly that he had fad been en through through1iore throUlh1l through1re
1iore 1l 1re re than he had expected Before B4 Beforeg fore foreging I j jteeing
teeing g sing to hi hY dressing dJealn room HoudinI Houdinlstated HoudinItated loudintstated
stated that fiftyseven minute mInutes wa w was the theIt1l1gest
1 It1l1gest > mgest time lie had ever been confined confinedin
in any wooden box boxThe boxThe boxThe
The box waa brought on the stage staget IiItageby stageby
t by > y the employee JIUlo and Houdlnis assist assistj1t 18t 18tant 1 1ant
ant j1t and thoroughly inspected by 900 900jf JOOIprsonll 300Jrsons
jf Iprsonll rsons who were compelled to take takeeats taketatB takeats
eats ats on the stage e because standing standingroim atandlnKHllm standingau
roim au rn could not be procured on any anyJloor anyror anytkor
Jloor of the th playhouse playhouseThe playhouaeThe playhouseThe
The committee on holding Houdini Houdinias
v as composed of Chairman J W Clouse ClouseI Clou
1 Iee Anderson Charles Birth Charles CharlesVollmer CharlesVoilmer
Vollmer Y nllmtr William llIIam Ziegler Earl Sanders Sandersand Sandera111 Sandersad I
and Wilt Butler Chairman douse e de dec deCJdld docided
CJdld c id id to put a few more screws screw in the thelX thebx their
lX ir and for fifteen minute his W fellow fellowmmitteemen fellowmmltteemen
4 mmitteemen straddled the case and andimvHl andIIlv and1i
imvHl IIlv 1i CI j screw 8CreW screws into the box as fast a aiwdrivers as aswdrlven asI
iwdrivers I could work worktlouoinl workt worklifluOlni
tlouoinl t 1 nualnl discovered tbe box was wa air airt air1t
11 1t t and asked that a a few small holes holesnored holeshtr holestred
nored htr 80 o a as to allow him to breath breathAt breathAt breathAt
At iu45 1o4 oclock Houdini seated him himself himselfn elf elfin
1 in n a chair cha on o the tJte platform above the theand thei
i S O and announced that he was r ready readylouse ady adyClouse adyJ
J > louse and one of the theater em emi emtook
i vesf V e took twenty yard yar s of t brand nw nwe
I > e half an inch in diameter and tied tiedi I IMnidini
Mnidini i 5 alinl in a way which the trickster trickster1ilinits trlckstetImits trickstertiiijts
ilinits Imits he b wa w was never bound befor beforeliairman beforc beforIjairman
c liairman Clouse and his men then thenI
I I if fd M d Houdini chair cha Ir and nd rope inside the theshowed theI
S < showed everyone thut he was Iili there thereiiiitl tberei
i iiiitl lid u then prepared to put on the lid B Bi Be BeI Be BeI
i sir if J doing this he handed Houdini a astai atal ata1
< stai tal card written by a skeptical in iniiKtual inliiiual
iiKtual 11 olual who claimed Houdini had a aml aI aS
S tS ml iOlo I assisting aamUft him At 1100 Houdlnis Houdlnisi
i < I plush IU5 spook house was placed placedfr placedfr
I 5 fr f the box This being done the the or orI ortra orplSYed
< I atra tra played at a a furious rate and the theiti theliUtne thesettied
iti liUtne < Jien < e settled down to wait waitJiut waitJt
Jiut as the hands of the stage clock clockjointed clocklinted clock1Inted I
jointed to midnight Houdini jumped jumpeddown jumpedoft
down oft the platform His HI appearance appearanceindicated appearanceindicated appearancelnhcated
indicated that he had a strenuous time timeiusi timethe I
iusi 1l1SIIIe le the case Hi H His arms were scarred scarredny
hy b ny the rope and nd there were blisters on oni onSis
tis i Sis is hands hand Houdini handed the postal postalt
t Mr Close took his hi coat from the thephuiorm theJII1ttorm
phuiorm 11 1 LI Oflfl and andleft led the stage He reap
l pired > ired a moment later and assisted the
Knane j nlbe employee in removing the cover coverl c cwertu > ver verto
l to < tf thft that the box was empty
Houdini congratulated ihe manufac ¬
titer tl ter l of the box box and said it was one oneof onef onet1
of f the th hardest Jobs he had ever under underIt undertlkfn underttkfl
Weak tlkfnWeak tlkfn Lungs LungsIt I
It is the old story of a weak throat throata
a tendency to weak lungs in the fam family family farnily ¬
ily You no no sooner get rid of yourold youroldcold your old oldcold oldcold
cold than a new one takes its place placeAyers placeAyers placeAyers
Ayers Cherry Pectoral breaks up upthis upthis upthis
this takingcold talt1n cold habit It strength strengthens strengthens strengthens ¬
ens heals Ask your doctor the thevery theI thevery
very next time you see him what whathe whathe whathe
I he thinks of Ayers Cherry Pectoral PectoralWte PectoralWI
I</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1907-09-01/ed-1/seq-36/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>.From a symposium on knots, dur
ing which Houdini expressed. his pro
found contempt for people who per
mitted ' themselves to be irrevocably
lashed to the mast or tied to the
burning sta*ke, the conversation drift
ed to what • Houdini considered his
mbst thrilling feat — a leap from the
Detroit river bridge in December,
when, ice was floating. This versa
tility was supernal; just the minute
before Houdini had handed me a mag
azine; "The Conjurers' Monthly."
What other .magazine editor ever
jumped from aTbridge? But Houdini
not only jumped from the bridge; but
he wore handcuffs when he did it.
In his' magazine Houdini uses the
muckrake oh Robert Houdin, a prede
cessor in magic.
"Youmust have been able to help
people out of predicaments, Houdini,"
I. suggested, seeking another chapter
in the. career of this man.
"I was in a hotel, the Zum Kaiser
hof, in Hanover, Germany, in 1902
when the place got on fire. I opened
the doors of 14 rooms. I could do
it quicker, than the people inside,
could turn the keys in the locks. The
proprietor said that if I ever came to
Hanover again and stopped , at any
place but his there would be trouble."
That was all he said about it, sim
ple narrative, and even those meager
details had to be probed out of him
with interrogation points.
Again we let the professional mat
ter lapse to consider the social ad
vantages of being a lock picker. Hou
dini^ told me two thrilling burglar
stories. These should go into the
5^ cent novel. Once, in Coffeyville,
Kans.. he was forced by a gang of
armed gamblers to pick the lock of
a gaming den that they might get in
to mark the cards. He picked the !
lock successfully, but jumped quickly
through the opened door into the area
and slammed it in the face of the
frustrated gamblers. They took a
shot at Houdini. He showed me the
bullet wound in the back of his hand.
Skill Aids Two Burglars</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-09-23/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>HOUDINI HAS FUN AT JAILERS
EXPENSE
EASILY GETS OUT OF THEIR
HANDCUFFS
Man Who Releases Himself from
Crushing Weight of Manacles
Defeats Cleverest Men
on the Force
Houdlnl again baf
fled the police and of
ficers and escaped
from their most dif
ficult "hardware" last
night at the Orphe
um. Officers Gardner
and La Niece, assist
ed by Jailer Gllpln,
fastened nearly one
hundred and twenty
pounds of shackles
and handcuffs on the
wrists and ankles of
the "handcuff king,"
from which it took
him exactly eight and
one-half minutes to
escape.
This is the second
attempt made by
these three officers to
defeat Houdlni. On
Saturday evening they
handcuffed his hands
behind his back and
drew the chains of the
leg Irons through the
iandcuff chains. In this difficult posi
tion, which compelled him to crouch upon
his knees, it took Houdinl fifteen min
utes to release himself.
Gardner, La Niece and Gllpin say that
they are not through with Houdini. and
Houdlni says that if it gives them pleas
ure to shackle him they are welcome
every evening. He offered one of the
trio a year's salary— Houdlni' s, not the
officer's— to repeat one of the simplest
of his tricks which the rtflcer had boast
ed of doing. Up to date the offer has
not been accepted.
HOUDINI
HUNDREDS WATCH CIRCUS
SETTLE DOWN FOR STAY
Clown Turns Somersault Onto Bull.
dog's Back and Animal Chases
Him from Tent — Girl
Subdues Lion</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-09-29/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>"In two minutes Houdini was out of
that cell, free, the lock holding htm hard
ly longer than it took him to get into the
place and get his bearings. Then, with
out the knowledge of the waiting officials
who had retired from view, Houdinl
quickly ran to the cells of Chase, Whit
ney, Mercer, Ferguson, Donovan, Gas
ktns, Backus and Howlett. To each oc
cupant the unclad cell-breaker seemed
like an apparition from some other world,
and the astonishment he created when he
commanded each to come out and follow
him can be better Imagined than de
scribed.
"Chase gave a gasp of fear, and then
cried: 'Have you come to let me out?
What are you doing without clothes?'
He supposed then that Houdinl was an
escaping fellow prisoner. He followed at
Houdinl's heels and the cell breaker
dashed with him down to the end of the
corridor, where he opened the cell con
taining Clarence Howlett.
" 'What are you doing here?' said Hou
dinl to the astonished Howlett. 'What
are you in for?'
" 'I'm a housebreaker,' said the pris
oner, as though maKlng his last confes
sion.
" 'You're a bad one,' said Houdinl, 'or
you could get out of here. Come along.'
Howlett followed his strange captor, and
Houdini then thrust Chase Into the cell
and rushed Howlett up to Chase's cell.
"This scene, strange and strenuous, was
repeated again and again, until every
desperate man was changed into another
cell than his own, All were in a tumult.
Twenty-one minutes after Houdini had
been locked in the cell he had done all
the julck changing and stood before his
free audience In the main hall, clothed as
in every day manner.-</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1907-09-29/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Harry Houdini Gives Throng of Spec
tators In Westlake Park Two
Minutes of Suspense While
Submerged
Five thousand spectators held their
breath in sympathy with Harry Hou
dini at Westlake park yesterday after
noon when the handcuff marvel did a
Count of Monte Crlsto stunt by leaping
into the lake heavily manacled.
"OOoo! I bet he's drowned," said a
small boy in awed and shuddery tones
when the man remained what seemed
an interminable time beneath the shim
mering water of the lake.
A small line of bubbles came to the
surface. Then larger bubbles arose
and a little cloud of mud drifted to tho
top. Five thousand shivers ran down
5000 spines.
"Oh, why doesn't he come up?" asked
a nervous old lady who had waited
HOUDINI, AS HE APPEA"ED WHEN
HE LEAPED INTO LAKE YES.
three hours for the opportunity to
worry about the fate of the misguided
youth.
"He's unlocking the shackles. Ho
will be up in a minute or two," said a
high school girl.
"Oh, dear, a minute or two Is enough
for him to drown In," was the dismal
reply.
• "Aw, he's stalling," shouted an Irre
pressible urchin.
"No he's not. He has to get them
shackles off first. He can't swim with
them on." This from a bright lad with
a wire bridle on his teeth who waited
two hours and went home with an
autograph which read: "Harry Hand
cuff Houainl." '
A man on the landing threw off his
coat and ran to the edge of the planks
looking intrntly into the water.
"He's going to jump," shouted the
throng.
"He's stuck In the mud. Someone
has got to rescue him," shouted a wise
guy who had seen Houdini Jump from
a bridge thirty feet high into 300 feet
of water or 300 feet high into thirty
feet of water. The crowd never got It
straight.
More bubbles. More mud. Then
Houdini canre slowly to the surface —
feet first!
"I told you he'd stuck his head into
the mud." said the wise guy. Then the
feet disappeared. A second later Hou
dini's head bobbed to the surface. He
made it dramatic and shivery enough to
satisfy even the small gamin who had
half hoped to see a drowning or at least
aTthrllHuK rescue scene.
Laden with heavy chains and hand
cuffs enough to restrain the county
road gang Houdini leaped from the
roof of the pavilion at Westlake park.
His hands were shackled behind him.
TbTM biff uatrolmen attended to that
little detail. There are some members
of the force who would have liked to
have defeated the handcuff king even
beneath the water.
With no free hand to guide him in
the headlong dive the man's body shot
forward in an almost horizontal posi
tion. With an indescribable midair
kick he righted himself and made a
pretty but dangerously vertical dive.
The shutters of 800 cameras clicked In
unison and the awful suspense began.
The horror only ended when the man's
smiling face appeared above the water
of the lake.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1914-07-16/ed-1/seq-16/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CROWD OF 15.000
WATCHES HOUDINI
Handcuff Expert, Shackled and
Boxed. Is Thrown Into Water
Rises in a Minute.
Fifteen thousand people in Battery
Park yesterday noon, cither saw or
tiied to sec Harry Houdini, known a?
the '?handcuff k,r.j.r." thrown into the
water from the tug J. A. McAllister.
The cro\?'d surged back aril forth
the water fronl with such force
that those in the front row alonn the
???a wall ' eed ab? tit mi'I, aided by po?
licemen, ri: I ack into the
park '
pu-heI into ' ? I n ''.or.
In the meantim? Houd ?,. ?vas having
all hard t ?me .?ii\ inu a**:
nio\ir,- picture photographers who in?
sisted upon reeling off his font di
id thai he had his 0?vn staff of
film-makeri on hand.
All these little troubles being ? I
tied, the newspapermen put the leg
irons and two pair of handcuff on
He ?va- then p;i: ii a pack?
ing box, the cover was nailed down and
boui '? ' ?tl steel tape, the whiatli
the tugboat end the "P. D, 7" I
rerboard ?vent the box, Houdini
and -dl.
In about one minute he appeared al
the surface. He had done it once be?
fore a-id had lived to hear the crowds
cheer him The spectator
r ting, some sr.ying that he k.-pt
the ke; s - h ick hair, other? thai
art - ' ! genius.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1915-12-08/ed-1/seq-14/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Week ago the h:g champion attended i
show at the Orprieiiin in that c ty ant
hid himself in the balcony. Houdin.
the handcuff king, was on the bill, an.
the audience did not know that Jes?
was la the house until Houdini, an i<
Utual in his act, stepped to the foot
lights and asked that a comm ttee ol
gentlemen come up on the ttsge to ?c?
? the I rtegofl ! i "' apscislist hat
nothing up hi< aleevoa ttt deceive s
gullible public. Ten good men anri
true meandered op to the ?tage, and
then Hoodini said:
"Now, I need three more gentlemen
up here There la a men here to-night
who doea not knoe thet I am swore "I
his presence. Hi- will be enough fot
gentlemen if he will
? ? ? on thia committee, He ia ?'??*?
Willsrd, our champion." Taken bv sur
priae, the ant for
? tecond or two and tl.?n broke info
tumultuou- ? been and
thrieki foi W llard filled the hoeae,
Houdini looked up in the banlcony
where Willard was seated und sa.?i:
"I will leave it to the audience, Mr.
Willard. Yyu BOS they want to see
you."
A fresh outburst of applause went
up foi
"Aw g'wan with your act." grow.el
W r.l when the applaoae hud sub
puled | bit. "I pan! fur mv seat here.'
"Rut, Mr. Willard," broke in Houdini,
.....
uGi?e me the same wagea you pay
those other fellows and I'll come
down," said Willard sullenly.
By thi? time the audience had be?
come quite still.
"Sir, 1 will ??la lly do to," returned
Houdini hotly. "Come on down I pay
these men nothing."
"Aw g'wan with the show." roared
Willard. Then the audience took a
hand. Beginning with a few hisse?, a
general demonstration against Willard
was launched in a fla-h. Houdini held
up his hand for silence. It was readily
gr: iited.
"Jess Willard, I have just paid you
a compliment," began Hottdlni dramati?
cally. "Now, I watit tu tell you some?
thing else. I will be Henry Houdini,
Je-,?. Willard, when you are NOT the
heavyweight champion of the world."
A roar of Bpplsoaa greeted Houdini'?
remarks. A deep rumble In the gal?
lery Indieeted that Willsrd was trying
to make sonic? sort .if reply, and the
Chsen for Hoodini suddenly veered
to groans and Loots. ??[ made a mis
? take," continued Houdini. "I asked
Boxing Bouts
for the Week</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1916-04-18/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>They are being sent out this week.
Houdini to Be Hanged
In Strait jacket at High
Noon Here Tomorrow
"Handcuff King" to Dangle 100
Feet In Air Before Crowds
At 12:30 o'clock.
WILL .EXTRICATE HIMSELF
Expert Knot Tiers Will Superin
tend Exhibition, to Which All
Are Invited.
Harry Houdlnl has heen cordcmned)
to be hanged! i
Ho will bo hanged at 12:30 tomorrow
In front of the Munsoy building In plain
view of all of tho thousands of Wash
lngtnr.tanu who can gather on Pennsyl
vania, avenuo.
The "Handcuff King" has escaped
from ovciythlng tho pollco or saVty
llrst artists of all sorts havo designed
to confine a vicious criminal and now
ho will reach tho end of hit rope! .
Tho end of tho rope will danglo 100
feet In mldnlr from the front of tho.
Munsey building -and Houdlnl will bol
attached to it by tho feet with, all tho
Ingenious knots the police or anybody
elan can devise .
Arms To Bo Rigid. I
Ho wil also havo his arms securely I
bourn, to his body and his body made
rigid with the most approved type of
straltjacket. All of these things will
be done to Insure the thorough hanging
of tint worker of magic.
And Houdlnl doclarea he will hang
only long enough to loose himself from
His lncumorances!
He laughs at tho proposition to hang
him. and declares those In charge of
the operation can go as far as they
like. He guarantees that he will free
himself. And It Is agreed that he shall
go fieo If ho docs get loose.
Tho rrocidura to be followed will bo
to confine Houdini in a regulation
straltjacket. A Jacket and two
husky attendants have been secured.
The men are experienced In restraining
dai.gcioiudy Insane patients. They havo
been instructed to use the most ap
proved Jacket a tvpo from which no
escape has ever been recorded.
Houdini hasn't seer, the Jacket that
vlll bo used apd will not see it until
they put It on him The two attendants
will see to It that tho "Handcuff King"
Is placid in tho Jacket In a way they
havo of putting men in Jicketa of the
samo kind for keeps. They state they
will put Houdlnl in the jirket for keeps,
as no ono they havo over put into one
of them has ever gotten out.
In Air 100 Feet.
Then a rone will bo nttached tn Hon.
dlnl's fet so that It will not come oil
ana tacKlo will bo attached to this
rope with which Houdlnl will be hoist
ed up about 100 feet and will dangle,
head down for
The exact length of time he will dan
gle Is all up to Houdlnl. Tho men
In charge will do It so well that they
Insist he will dangle until they let
him down. Houdini thinks otherwise.
He claim ho will be thero long enough
for an average person to wriggle an
oyellu about three times in deliberate
succession.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-01-06/ed-1/seq-34/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Houdini Has New
Elephant Trick
To-morrow at the Hippodrome one
; may sec a full sized, real, live elephant
disappear in full view of the audience
on a brilliantly lighted stage, before
one's very eyes. This vanishing ele?
phant illusion is an experiment con?
ceived and perfected by Houdini,
world renowned expert in extracation,
whom Charles Dillingham has selected
as ?i feature extraordinary of "Cheer
Up!" Tiie engagement of Houdini is
I it. keeping with Mr. Dillingham's policy
, o? introducing important new features
; ?n his big Hippodrome spectacles after
' the holidays.
The disappearing elephant feat is
i ono which Houdini began cxpcriment
! ing upon during his visit to India four
years ago, for it has long been the
dream'of the Indian fakirs to realize
I the reputation given to Chaucer hun?
dreds of years ago, when he wrote that
; he had seen "an elephant crumble to
1 the earth in piecemeal and then reas
i semble itself and walk away." Hou
| dini's illusion, which can no doubt be .
, classified as the "biggest" ever at
] tempted on any stage, while it does
not crumble the huge beast weighing
, over G.uOO pounds, it does actually van?
ish the elephant on the stage in full
glare of the light, without the use of
trapa, as the tank of water under the
Hippodrome r.pron prevents any such
' camouflage. Houdini has constructed a
; gigantic cylinder shaped container of
? such dimensions that the largest cle
| phant obtainable can enter with ease.
It walks through this tube and van?
ishes.'.
A second new experiment which Mr. .
i Dillingham will introduce next Mon- j
| day will be in the final scene of '
i "Cheer Up!" in the aquatic spectacle,
where Houdini will present his Sub- i
? mcrsible Mystery. In this daring ex
j hibitioji he is manacled and leg-tied
i and imprisoned in a heavily weighted
! iron bound box, which is lowered into j
I the tank of water. While submerged :
' Houdini accomplishes his escape and j
j comes to the surface unfettered.
L Now, to pro-re that he is actually</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://www.loc.gov/newspapers/?q=womens+suffrage</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025316/1917-01-28/ed-1/?sp=6&q=womens+suffrage&st=text&r=-0.208,-0.236,1.416,1.416,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>"We feel deeply indignant," declnres
the Women's Suffrage association,
"that the Interests of all women have
been sacrificed to those of a small per
centage of men. The stream of fine
words in which the Importance of
women's suffrage for the state was
demonstrated by the prime minister
and by many deputies, has turned out
to be but empty sounds. It has been
acknowledged that women's suffrage
lies in the spirit of the times, that it
must and will speedily come also In
this country, and it is incomprehensi
ble that courage should have been lack
ing to grant the vote to women in this
constitutional revision. This inconse
quence of the second chamber compels
women to resume the stuggle in the
country, a struggle which will be hard
er and bitterer than ever."
However, the women are not entire
ly disappointed, for under the revised
constitution just passed, members of
their sex will be eligible for the pro
inclal councils and for the council of
state. Moreover, the constitutional
holt has been removed from the door
that bars the way to actual women's
suffrage: if the bills in question final
ly reach the state book, women will be
able to get the coveted vote by an ordi
nary legislative measure that is a bare
parliamentary majority, which was im
possible before.
Opposition was offered by various
members of the right even to these
concessions. Votes for women were
objected to as in conflict, with the call
ing of women as wife and mother, by
the orthodox, old-fashioned, conserva
tive Dutchmen.
The prime minister, Mr. Cort van
Linden, who is himself in favor of worn
en's suffrage, had the parliamentary
wisdom to take what he could get and
he refused at present to embody votes
for women in the constitution on the
ground that women's suffrage would
have to be universal if placed there at
all, so that all women, even those who
did not desire it or were opposed
thereto, would be called u|K>n to go to
the polling both. He apparently thinks
more sufragist educational work among
women is needed and that the vote
should be conferred by a more gradual
process.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060379/1919-10-04/ed-1/?sp=7&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>WOMAN SUFFRAGE IN iTALY
THE Italian Parliament has passed women’s suffrage. The measure
went through both the Chamber and the Senate last week. The meas
ure now agreed to is the Martini Bill, which gives votes to all adult women,
but provides that they shall not vote at the next Parliamentary elections.
The reason for this delay is a purely practical one, the difficulty of mak
ing the necessary additions to the Parliamentary register in time. It
will, no doubt, be a disappointment to ardent suffragists, who have been
working for the vote for years and wish to take part in the after-war
reconstruction of their country. Time, however, is really needed for
educating the future voters in their responsibilities. Italian women have
been held back by legislative and social custom, and there is a terrible
amount of illiteracy among them, especially in the South. The awaken
ing in the last two years has, however, been remarkable. Among the
interesting signs of it are two very excellent weekly women’s papers,
II Cimento of Rome and La Voce Nuova of Milan. Both are full of in
teresting matter, and both are strongly suffragist and feminist in their
views.
WOMAN SUFFRAGE IN AFRICA
In the Continent of Africa women of British race have not been so
quick in obtaining their enfranchisement as in New Zealand, Australia,
America, and Europe. But there also the spirit of the age is moving.
Rhodesia and British East Africa have now got woman suffrage, and in
South Africa suffragists are full of hope. It is only six years since the
white men first claimed the vote in the British East Africa Protectorate.
Four years later white women began to make the same claim, and the East
Africa Women’s League was formed. Its work was crowned with suc
cess last April. The Governor, Sir Edward Northey, gave his casting
vote in favor of the enfranchisement measure, saying that he believed
there was a real mandate for women’s suffrage. In Rhodesia the Women’s
Enfranchisement ordinance was promulgated on July 4. Both these meas
ures make women eligible for the legislative councils of their States be
sides giving them votes.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016025/1903-01-13/ed-1/?sp=9&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Majority of Women Do Not Care
For Right of Suffrage.
MIERESTiNG MEETiNG OF ANUS.
Mrs. George of BrooMine Presents
Other Side of Argument.
The other side of the woman's suf
frage question was presented yester
day afternoon before a iarge number
of women at the Second Advent
church. The speaker was Mrs
George of Brookiine, Mass., and she
presented in the course of an address
of about an hour some strong argu
ments why the baliot shouid not be
given to women.
Mrs. George came to Portiand tc
speak on anti-suffrage at the request
of some women here who do not favoi
the biii which is pending before the
iegisiature granting the right of suf
frage to the property hotding and tax
paying women when municipai mat
ters are concerned.
Mrs. George began by saying that
white there are a iarge number of in
teliigent. zeaious and enthusiastic
women in this country and in this
State who favor the enfranchisement
of women, there are just as iarge a
number of women who* are not in fa
vor of this being done and who do not
beiieve that women wiii be the gainers
by being given the priviiege
of the baiiot. She said
that since the first women's suffrage
meeting in Seneca Faiis, New York, in
1848 woman has been given a great
many more opportunities than she had
at that time but in no way can they
be attributed to the efforts of the suf
fragists. On the contrary they have
come to women because of the justice
of man. In 1848 there were but seven
occupations open to women outside of
the home white today there are over
four hundred. Then women did not
have the priviiege of the higher edu
cation to any great degree but the same
The Secret Of Long Life
Consists in keeping al! the main or
gans of the body in heaithy. reguiar
action, and in quickiy destroying dead
iy diseas germs. Electric Bitters reg
uiate Stomach. Liver and Kidneys, pu
rify the biood, and give a spiendid ap
petite. They work wonders in curing
Kidney Troubies, Femaie Complaints,
Nervous Diseases. Constipation, Dys
pepsia, and Maiaria. Vigorous heaith
and strength aiway$ foiiow their use.
Oniy 50c at C. H. Guppy Co.'s.
is not true today for woman has the
same opportunity as man in tho culti
vation of her mind. Sincy that time
there has aiso been a great change in
the taws reiating to women but in the
fifty years the suffrage movement for
women has been in progress, there
have been none of these iaws adopted
which can be said to have been due to
the influence of the suffragists aione
but are due to the sense of justice of
man. If women be given the right of
the baiiot she wiii iose many of the
special priviieges which she now en
joys under these iaws and there is no
state in the union whose iaws are more
favorabie to women than are those of
Maine. Ait of these changes in the
iaws which are beneficial to women
have come without the demands of
women and why, as some one has said,
should the women stilt haii the car
when it has stopped at the crossing for
them?
Woman, unlike man, is born to a pro
fession. that of home making. There
she finds work for her stiii to do and in
doing it she may have more influence
upon the worid than she possibly couid
have at the baiiot box. She trains the
youth of the country who become vot
ters and it is her especiai priviiege and
duty to see to it that the youth is
trained to become good citixens. One
exponent of woman's suffrage has said,
in an eloquent period that in this
growing worid women's domain is no
ionger confined to the kitchen but is
the worid. Woman has not so far ful
filled her duties in the kitchen, how
ever. that she can neglect them for the
worid.
Giadstone said at one time he had be
lieved in women's suffrage but when so
many iaws had been enacted for the
benefit of women he had come to the
conciusion that women did not require
the suffrage. The anti-suifrage women
believe that women have their own
work to do and it is not at aii necefe
sary for their happiness or their weii
being that they go out into the worid
td usurp the duties which beiong to
the men. The speaker said that there
are many women suffragists who reai
]y betieve that woman is needed in the
Held of poiitics because her votes wii!
better the iaws and the worid but until
the women suffragists are abie to give
some proof that women—now much re
moved from the world of poiitics and
not in touch with it or at aii iikeiy to
be, even if she has the right of the bai
iot—until they give some proof that
they will be abie to vote more inteiii
gentiy than do men it is not weii for
them to be given that priviiege. Over
eighty-three per cent of the women
in this country are now about the home
white man finds his iife outside the
home in the busy worid. Because of
this fact man knows the condi
tions of the worid much better than
women wiil ever be able to know them.
The speaker argued that now woman is
non partisan and with the privilege of
petition and appeal she can exert in
fluence which she would otherwise be
unabie to exert- Ih illustration of
this she toid how the women of Massa
chusetts had been enabled to secure a
large appropriation for play grounds in
Boston and aiso to secure an appro
priation for a woman's reformatory.
H^d they been voters and partisans
these appropriations they wouid have
found it most difhcult to secure but as
it was they coaid approach legislators
and ask for things with as much hope
of success as can their husbands, who
now vote.
It woutd not be patriotic to ask that
women be aiiowed to vote untii it can
be assured that women wiii vote with
more steadiness and better than can the
average man today. Unless it can be
shown that this wiii be the resuit the
women suffragists mereiy ask for the
doubling of the vote and the increase
in the number of irresponsibie and un
inteiiigent voters. This is not what the
country needs today b.ut what it needs
is more intelligent and better voting.
The speaker then dweit more upon the
influence which woman may exert upon
the affairs of state by showing that in
Massachusetts eieven-tweifths of the
teachers of primary and grammar
schoois are women and there they have
am opportunity of accomplishing far
more Jhan they can at the bailot box.
Besides this the leisure class among
Women now have the opportunity of
engaging in public work and of doing
far more good than couid ever be the
case if they were endowed with the
priviiege of voting and regarded as
partisans.
The women suffragists once ciaimed
that it w as the inherent right of women
to vote but that contention is not heard
now? because time and again the courts
of the iand have decided that the tight
to vote is not an inherent right but a
deiegatcd right. Women, like men,
have the inherent right to iife, liberty
and the pursuit of happiness but not to
suffrage.
Once more the speaker said that untii
women can prove that they can vote
better than men they shouid not ask
for the right to vote and those women
who through indifference do not protest
shouid express their disapproval of the
idea or they wiii be counted as favoring
it.
One of the ciaims of the suffragists
is that the women are needed to puri
fy poiitics. That they wiii be abie to
purify potities cannot be demonstrated
untii it is proved that the average
women is better than the average man.
One of the ways of the suffragists is to
take a woman far above the average
and compare her with a man far beiow*
the average man.
The speaker went on to say that the
reason for this meeting was the biii
now pending before the legisiature for
the right of municipal suffrage for
property hoiding women. She said that
this was a most atiuring pian to enter
the thin wedge for women's universal
suffrage to women is plausible on its
face but the speaker said that the argu
ments wouid not bear inspection. She
characterized the pending measure as
un-American and said that in this
country the granting of the right to
vote to the property holding class alone
had long since been done aw ay w ith in
most states and joday it is the man who
can bear the musket to enforce the
laws he votes for who is aiiowed to
vote and not the man who ow ns prop
erty.
She said that the women who favor
The Presidents Stave to Catarrh.—1) T.
Sample, president of Sample's Instalment
Company. Washington, Pa., writes: "For years
I was amicted with Chormc Catarrh. Reme
dies and treatment by specialists only gave me
temporary relief until t was Induced to use I r.
Agnew's Catarrhal Powder. It gave atmost in
stant relief, so cents.
Sold by John W. Pei bins and T. L. Foss
90n, druggists Portland, Me.
women's suffrage are fond of referring
to the fight of the American colonies
against Great Britain when the issue
was "no taxation without representa
tion." She said that one suffragist had
gone so far as to say that King George
was a Moody tyrant and that women
today must fight against her common
enemy, man. She said that this argu
ment wouid not appiy to the present
matter because in the case of the Amer
ican coionies it was a nation which de
manded representation and not a few
individual.
Mrs. George said that some of the
women who have signed the petition
now before the iegisiature as tax pay
ing women pay taxes oniy on bicycles.
Mrs. George also said that it was not
the wage earning women whom this
measure wouid heip because the wage
earners, as a genera! thing, are not
property owners but the bill would al
low to vote only those who had in
herited their property or to whom it
had been transferred by unscrupulous
men who desired their suffrage.
She said that women's suffrage in the
three Mormon states of Idaho, Wy
oming and Utah and aiso in Colorado
was not a great success and neither
was it so very successfui in Austraiia,
the paradise of experiments. Today
there is no such privileged class in the
world as women and they can't have
these privileges and the right to vote
aiso. They must give up one or the
other.
At the conclusion of Mrs. George's
address which was heartiiiy appiauded
she asked the women present to sign
the petitions protesting against the pas
sage of the pending bill and many did
so.
Mrs. Ogden, wife of Canon Ogden,
aiso spoke briefly and said that there
is to be an organization of the women
opposed to the enfranchisement of
women in Maine.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042303/1920-09-14/ed-1/?sp=3&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060379/1913-10-25/ed-1/?sp=8&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
Published Weekly
By the Just Government League of Maryland.
Editors:
DR. AND MRS. DONALD R. HOOKER,
Cliffhurst, Mt. Washington, Md.
Contributing Editors:
Dr. Thaddeus P. Thomas, Mrs. Wm. J. Brown,
Mrs. John G. Wilson, Dr. O. Edward Janney,
Dr. Florence R. Sabin, Miss Ellen N. La Motte,
Rev. James Grattan Mythen.
Managing Editor:
Miss M. B. Dixon,
817 N. Charles Street.
Business Manager:
MRS. CHARLES JOSEPH OGLE,
Sylvanside, Kenwood Avenue, Catonsville.
Subscription Rates:
DOMESTIC.
One Year SI.OO Three Months on Trial 25
Six Months 50 Single Copy 05
CANADIAN. FOREIGN.
One Year $1.50 One Year $1.50
RECEIPT of payment must not he expected to show on address label under two
weeks from date received. Instructions for RENEWAL, DISCONTINUANCE or
CHANGE OP ADDRESS should be sent two weeks before the date they are to go into
effect. IJotli old and new addresses must always be given.
Checks and drafts and postofflce orders should be made payable to The Maryland
Suffrage News.
Advertising rates will be sent upon application to advertising manager.
BALTIMORE, OCTOBER 25, 1913
SEE THE DEMOCRATIC CANDIDATES
Suffragists who have not taken part in the interviewing of the Dem
ocratic candidates for the General Assembly should be up and doing.
The election is near at hand. After November 6 the men elected will
be far less approachable than they are now.
Since we ask only that the question of woman suffrage shall be re
ferred to the voters, the candidates for the General Assembly can find
little reason for refusing to cast a favorable vote on the proposition when
it is presented at Annapolis. If they do so refuse they can be placed in
very bad odor with their constituency. The voters at large, regardless
of their attitude on this particular question, do not wish to have the Leg
islature take unto itself the right of final decision on issues of popular
government, and it is generally realized that there is a sufficient demand
for the submission of our enfranchisement to the present electorate to
justify the suspicion that something is wrong if a man refuses to in
dorse it.
We should, therefore, in these last days enter heartily into the work
of interviewing candidates. Where the Democrats are unreasonable it
becomes our duty to urge our voting friends to cast their ballots for can
didates in the other parties, all of whom may be counted upon to vote
right. The balance of power is too insecure in this State to allow the
Democrats to overlook the votes which we are now able to change in
various parts of the State.
THE UNEXPURGATED CASE AGAINST WOMAN SUFFRAGE
Under the above title Sir Almroth Wright of England has pub
lished a book attacking woman suffrage. It is masculinely militant,
judging from the reviews—for we have not as yet seen the book itself.
But, perhaps, if for no other reason, the author should be commended
for his frankness. He sees in woman a caste physically, intellectually
and morally inferior to man. This caste has been educated to its own
and the world’s detriment. Unsatisfied sexuality, accentuated by mate
inability to think and reason account, according to the distinguished
author, for each and every suffragist. “The happy wife and mother is
never passionately concerned about the suffrage.”
The book would appear to be a rehash of the old argument with which
we are familiar, stated after the fashion, we may suppose, adopted by
the politicians who seek by vulgarity to keep woman out of politics.
The accusation that woman “arrives at conclusions on incomplete evi
dence” will appeal particularly to those who are familiar with at least
one of Sir Almroth’s scientific theories.
We recommended the book, even on our hearsay evidence, to those
HELP THE CAUSE.—Mention the Maryland Suffrage News When Patronizing Our Advertisers.
MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
who still believe that a nation can live half slave and half free. For it
purposes to divide the world forever into the strong and the weak, the
male and the female, the master and the slave. Out of this division
shall come greatness, but greatness only to the strong, the male and the
master. That other half shall sacrifice and be sacrificed. It is proper
that there should be inequality in the law, the wage and the pursuit of
happiness, for by these means we may cultivate to the fullest that frail
flower, the male child, and make him sole master of his home.
SUFFRAGE IN FOREIGN LANDS
Belgium.—Woman suffrage in Belgium is in a curious political posi
tion. It is supported by the Conservative and Catholic Party, and bit
terly opposed by the Liberals. The Socialists are theoretically in favor
of votes for women—it is part of their program —but as they are united
with the Liberal Party in their electoral campaign for the abolition of
plural voting, they are apparently willing to waive the women’s question;
at any rate, they consider it an inopportune moment for discussing it at
present. The Government has appointed a commission to inquire into
the whole question of political representation. Many of the 31 members
of the commission are in favor of the enfranchisement of women, and
the Federation Beige pour le Suffrage des Femmes is collecting relevant
information on the voting rights of women and the effect of their repre
sentation in other countries, to lay before the commission. Last year
women workers were given the suffrage for the Conseils de Prudhomme
on the same terms as men.
France.—The woman’s movement has made real progress lately.
Public opinion seems inclined to regard women’s claims with favor.
When the French Chamber reassembles this autumn M. Ferdinand
Buisson will move the discussion of the favorable report of the Univer
sal Suffrage Committee of the Chamber, which he has already presented.
Recently the Municipal Council of the City of Paris and the General
Council of the Seine both unanimously passed the following resolution:
“This Council, having approved the claim of Frenchwomen to the
municipal vote, expresses the hope that the Dussansoy-Buisson bill may
be discussed as soon as possible.” The French being a logical nation,
it is anticipated that the granting of the municipal vote to women will
bring them nearer political enfranchisement than has been the case in
England. As a proof of the successful agitation of the French suf
fragists it may be mentioned that a law for the assistance of mothers has
been carried after being hung up in the Senate for 13 years, and that
Madame Marie Verone, a barrister, has been appointed a member of the
Extra Parliamentary Commission to draft a bill for child protection.
Recently le Matin has opened its columns to a correspondence on the
subject of votes for women, and many leading Frenchwomen have con
tributed excellent letters in favor of the enfranchisement of their sex.
Germany.—The Fifth General Assembly of the German Union for
Women’s Suffrage is to be held at Eisenach early in October. There
are 23 country associations affiliated to the union, and 90 branches. A
large public meeting is to be held during the assembly, which will last
three days, when the subject of Woman’s Wage-Labor and Women’s
Suffrage will be discussed by professional women and industrial workers.
Forty petitions in favor of granting the municipal vote to women have
been presented this year in the Prussian Diet; it is noteworthy that it
is not only the suffrage societies, but other women’s organizations that
are carrying on the agitation for the municipal vote.
A DUTY OF CITIZENSHIP
Personal affairs of the woman, quite as much, if not more than those
of the man, are public affairs. Public affairs are, after all, so very per
sonal that women will soon wonder how they dared neglect them so long.
Both men and women are thus sure to learn that politics is not of itself'
“dirty” or to be shunned, but is as vital as life, as personal as home, as
sacred as religion. She or he who fails to take her or his part in it, in
telligently, independently, conscientiously, is not only failing to do the
duty of a patriot, but to do his or her duty to self or loved ones. Outside
interests are inside the house. Those inside the home have interests out
side. —Graham Taylor.
TESTIMONY FROM THE JUVENILE COURT
In the report of the Juvenile Court for the year ending April 30,
1913, a subtle suffrage argument comes to light. Against the 2798 bad
boys who were haled into the Juvenile Court for various offenses during
the 12 months covered by the report, the small number of girls brought
before the judiciary during the same time seems to stand out in bold
proof of their superior virtue, for against the 2798 bad boys the number
of bad girls is but 349.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86076142/1916-08-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>August 1. News (if Hughes' announcement for a suffrage amendment was
received with unbounded enthusiasm at the hcndiiiiiirters hero of (lie Congressional Union. State
ments of leaders declared the women of the west would rally, to t lie support of Hughes, contrasting
his attitude with that of Wilson insisting that suffrage was a state issue.
CHARLES EVANS HUGHES
Republican Nominee for Preeldent
e-o-e-o mnn
NEW YORK, August I. Charles
Evans Hughes was formally notified
of hh nomination as the candidate of
the Republican party for the office of
president at a mass meeting held at
Carnegie hall last evening. The huge
auditorium was packed to capacity
and the Btage was occupied by the
leading national celebrities' of the
party. The meeting was opened by
Warren H. Harding, chairman of the
Chicago convention, addressing him-!
self to the candidate as follows:
"Mr, Hughes: The committee here
assembled, representing all of the
Vnlted States and territories, chosen
by the Republican National conven
tion which met in Chicago on last
June 7, is directed by that convention
formally to notify you of its action in
selecting you as its nominee for. the
presidency of the republic.
"Speaking for the committee, it is
my pleasure to say directly what was
conveyed to you by telegraph, while
I he convention was yet in session
i lull you are the unanimous choice of
the Republican National convention
for the party standard bearer.
"That convention uttered the prin
ciples of a confident, determined, re
united and enthusiastic Republican
party which turns to you, in highest
respect and trust, as a nominee best
typifying the party's purposes and
Hie people's desires.
"Inasmuch as the unusual circum
stances inspired an informal notice
at the time of the convention's action
and you then made an informal ac
ceptance of the call to patriotic1 duty,
wheh won the plaudits of our people.
I shall not refer In detail to the
action of the convention or the de
clared principles to which the Repub
lican party is committed. Uut it is
fitting that I should speak the con
gratulations of this committee on
your most extraordinary nomination.
It has no parallel in the history of
the Republican party. As the whole
people have approvngly wtne.iscd.
you have been chosen for leadership
by a convention which comprised the
best thought, the highest intention
and deepest consecration of a great
and historic party, when you were
not only not an aspirant but dis
couraged all endeavors In your
half.
"Notwithstanding your holding aloof
from all conference and participation,
that unfailing understanding which
directs popular sentiment to highest
victory called you to the service of
the party and the nation. Your rec
ord of public service, your well
known and courageous views on pub
lie questions when in executive post
ton, your abiding devotion to Republi
canism, your possession of a confi
dence which has united all believers
In Republican policies under our
party banner, your unalterable and
abiding Americanism, your high per
sonal character and well known capa
city all these have fixed you in the
American mind as the best exponent
of Republican principles and the
wisest leader to restore American
prestige and efficient government.
We bring it in the highest apprecia
te that leadership. We bring It in
full confidence that the people will
gladly acclaim the Republican restor-
I -X A

be- JtSZi l I
4 'X A ef V 1 I
y j
I CHARLES W. Ff)IR.BANK3
(Continued on Page 4.)
WOMAN'S SUFFRAGE
MEETS APPROVAL
I By Aiauvlalrd l-rraa.l
NKW Y()HK, August 1. C K. Hughes declared for an amend
nient to th federal cmistitution providing for women's suffrage.
1 1 is view were made pijldic in a letter written to Senator Suther
land of Utah.
Hughes' letter was in reply to a telegram received from the
senator asking the' nominee to define his personal position regarding
an equal suffrage federal amendment. Hughes replied: "Your
telegram received. In answer to the notification, I have not referred
to the proposed federal amendment relating to women's suffrage
because it win not mentioned in the platform. I have no ohjectiou,
however, to Mating my views. As I said in my speech, I think it
most desiralde that the question of women's suffrage he settled
promptly. The question should he settled for the entire country.
My view is that the proposed amendment should be submitted,
ratified and the subject removed from political discussion."
a e a e e e e e e -a</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060379/1913-06-07/ed-1/?sp=7&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Correspondents to the Maryland Suffrage
News are requested to address all communi
cations for the Letter Box to Mrs. Franklin
P. Mall, 1514 Bolton street; to use one side
of paper only, to leave space for heading,
write legibly, and have letter in such condi
tion that it can be forwarded immediately
to the printer.— Ed.
Dear Editors:
Do you not think a strenuous ef
fort should be made to counteract
the harm that is being done by the
English militants to the suffrage
cause with us? Of course, it seems
absurd to us that their conduct
should injure us here, for we never
have been militant, and there is not
the slightest danger of our men ever
driving us to use the methods of the
English women. Still, the fact re
mains that many people are being
prejudiced against the whole cause
of freedom for women because a
few English women are using mas
culine methods of settling difficul
ties. I think our speakers should
spend much of their energy in com
bating this prejudice, and that let
ters, not of approval, but of explan
ation, should be written to the pa
pers.
The attitude of most of us is ex
cellently expressed in a letter which
I have received from a California
woman who has taken an active part
in the suffrage work, and also in the
excellent reform legislation which
the women have helped to have en
acted in that State. Speaking of her
suffrage friends, she says:
“All these women are much op
posed to the militant policy. While
honoring Mrs. Pankhurst and the
English suffragettes for their hero
ism, they feel that their policy is
very bad for the suffrage cause all
over the world, and particularly in
America, where any form of mili
tancy is avoided. I believe all that
good American men need is to be
convinced that the women want the
vote, and that they need it for the
protection of the homes, the schools
and working women; that the
women stand for moral force in the
community.
“Anything that will arouse sex
antagonism, or make men feel that
we depend on physical force (a
plane in which we are beaten before
we start if we play fair) instead of
on peaceful moral forces, will re
tard suffrage here a generation, I
believe. An appeal to force, be
cause men in past ages found it nec
essary to appeal to force, is a back
ward movement and out of harmony
with the world movement toward
peace and a legal and moral settle
ment of disputes.”
I hope our Maryland women will
express similar sentiments on all
possible occasions. M. M.
CHURCH HOSTILE TO
WOMEN DELEGATES
Efforts of the Oregon Equal Suf
frage Association to extend the
sphere of women into the governing
body of the Protestant Episcopal
Church failed when the twenty-fifth
annual convention of the Diocese of
Oregon unanimously laid on the ta
ble a resolution demanding repre
sentation in the diocesan convention.
Chancellor R. L. Gilsan said the
constitution and canons of the Epis
copal Church were antagonistic to
according women such representa
tion at this time.
MRS. CHARLES WHITMAN
BRAVES RAIN FOR
SUFFRAGE
That women workers for suffrage
are never discouraged by a little
thing like the weather was again
proved the other day when Mrs.
Whitman, wife of the district attor
ney of New York, stood for an hour
on a soap box with the rain beating
down upon her, and turned the
voiceless speech in front of the
headquarters of the Woman Suf
frage Party. Mrs. Whitman also
walked in the suffrage parade on
May 3.
A WOMEN’S PILGRIMAGE
Non-Militants Will “Hike” for Cause
in England.
The National Union of Women’s
Suffrage Societies of Great Britain
J. W. BERRY SON
Furniture
UPHOLSTERING AND CABINET MAKING
887 N. Howard St. 312 W. Biddle St
BALTIMORE, MD.
Antique and Repair Work a Specialty.
C. P. Phone, Mt. Vernon 4687.
ITWTAKE the Suffrage
News support it- g
self.
Get us an ad. g
M Poultry and Eggs For Sale
AT MARKET PRICES
White Plymouth Rocks, Houdans and
Pekin Duck Eggs for hatching.
MISS N. K. WARNER, Catonsville, Md.
Telephone, Catonsville 39-R
I It pays to Advertise
in the Suffrage News
HELP THE CAUSE.—Mention the Maryland Suffrage News When Patronizing Our Advertisers.
MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
(a non-militant, but very powerful
body) is planning the biggest thing
it has ever done in the way of a
demonstration. The plan, briefly, is
that each of its federations shall or
ganize a Women’s Suffrage Pil
grimage to march from its home to
London, joining the other federa
tions on the way. Each procession
will hold meetings, distribute litera
ture and collect subscriptions during
the pilgrimage, the final goal being a
great Hyde Park meeting on July
26. The keynote of the pilgrimage
will, it is said, be the joyousness of
self-dedication to a great cause.
There will be nothing dismal about
it. Every pilgrim will have in her
heart a deep sense of happiness that
it has fallen to her lot to have the
chance of dedicating herself to one
of the greatest movements which
has ever taken place in the history
of the world.
MISS A. M. LARKIN RESIGNS
To prepare herself further for
office work, Miss A. M. Larkin,
office secretary of the Just Govern
ment League, has decided to take a
course at a business college, and has
temporarily given up her work at
headquarters. Miss Edith Heiser
of the Y. W. C. A., who is now cor
responding secretary of the league,
has been appointed in Miss Larkin’s
place. Sincere regret is felt by the
members of the league at Miss Lar
kin’s resignation, but it is hoped that
her absence from headquarters will
be of short duration. The league is
to be congratulated on securing
Miss Reiser's services meanwhile.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060379/1914-01-10/ed-1/?sp=6&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>CHILD LABOR AND WOMAN SUFFRAGE
Welfare of Working Children Important Where Women Are Enfranchised.
The National Child Labor Committee has announced that although
it will have only twelve campaigns on hand this winter (because the
t Legislatures of most of the States are not in session this year), it will
have enough work to keep it from feeling dull. The Child Labor Bulle
tin says ‘‘the eight hours a day for children is the crucial question nowa
days. In Massachusetts the textile interests are threatening to repeal
this ‘obnoxious clause’ in the new child labor law.” Last year California
passed a child labor law and provided for an Industrial Welfare Com
mission to make mandatory regulations concerning wages, hours and con
ditions of labor for women and minors. Colorado, Oregon and Wash
ington established similar commissions. All of these States have equal
suffrage. It would be interesting to see what would happen in any one
of these States if an attempt were made to repeal any laws for the bene
fit of children. It is however practically certain that no such attempt
would be successful, since women, once they are granted the franchise,
are thoroughly alive to their responsibilities and their powers.
VOTES FOR WOMEN IN ITALY
Feminist Movement a Live One.
The Congress for Woman Suffrage, recently held in Rome, closed on
December 8. It was attended by several members of Parliament and
representatives of the following political parties: Radical, Republican,
Constitutional Democratic, Reform Socialist and Official Socialist. A
resolution was adopted, in spite of opposition from the Milan Women’s
Socialist Group, “to appoint delegates in the various parties which repre
sent Constitutional Democracy, and unite them, in order to form a
parliamentary group, without distinction of party, ready to fight for the
women’s movement in Parliament.”
ENGLISH NON-MILITANT SUFFRAGISTS ADOPT NEW POLICY
Asquith’s Failure to Keep Promises Made the Reason for Change of Tactics.
The National Union of Women’s Suffrage Societies has issued the
following statement: Throughout the year 1913 the battleground was
transferred from the country to the House of Commons and here women
were led to believe that there was to be finally a free vote on the merits
of the suffrage question. It is not necessary to recapitulate the fiasco
of that week in January. None of the pledges given by Mr. Asquith
in 1911 were fulfilled. Evidence of the tactical reasons behind the fail
ures of the amendments, and the subsequent defeat of the Dickerson bill,
only confirmed the Union’s conviction that henceforth no reliance was
1o be placed on the possibility of a free vote for a Private Measure. It
resolved to concentrate on the demand for a Government Measure and
to develop the policy of the Union by increasing pressure on the Govern
ment in the constituencies, directing attack on the seats of Anti-Suffragist
Ministers, and further strengthening the position of the only party in
the House of Commons which had made Women’s Suffrage an integral
part of its policy.
WHY WORKING WOMEN NEED THE VOTE
Women Employes of Ford Motor Co. Not to Share in Company’s Profits.
The Ford Motor Company will at once put into operation a profit
sharing plan by which $10,000,000, representing approximately one-half
the profits of the Company, will be distributed annually among its em
ployees. According to tbe press statements announcing this plan, the
women employees will not share in the distribution of profits “not being
considered tbe economic factors that men workers are,” although the
women as well as the men will have increased wages. In California,
where women vote, two hundred men employed in the garment makers’
trade recently went on strike, not because of dissatisfaction with their
own wages, but because the wages of 150 women employed in the same
trade were too low. The employers then offered to increase the wages
of the'women, at the expense of the men (that is by lowering the wages
of the men) and the women, not to be outdone in generosity, refused to
accept the increase. California women it seems are not only economic
factors, but are also the recipients of the chivalry of which one frequently
hears from anti-suffragists.
A PERIPATETIC SUFFRAGE SCHOOL
Conference to Be Held in Eight of the Campaign Districts of New York.
School teaching is the latest role undertaken by Mrs. Chapman Catt
and Dr. Anna Howard Shaw, who are the acknowledged suffrage lead
ers of the United States. Practically all of New York State will come
under their jurisdiction for the coming month, since conferences com
bined with schools for suffrage workers will be held in eight of the
Campaign Districts in the months of January and February. Dr. Shaw
HELP THE CAUSE.—Mention th« Maryland tuffrag* New* When Patronizing Our Advertisers.
MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
will speak at each of the conferences, and Mrs. Catt will be present
throughout the entire time in each District.
Mrs. Catt writes in the “Woman Voter,” apropos of the work of edu
cating New York State to vote for the suffrage amendment, “If I could
have my way I would transform two classes of people at the outset.
These are not the anti-suffragists and the voters as the casual reader
might think. Instead, one is the optimistic suffragist who knows that
“suffrage is surely coming and rests secure in the faith that the mys
terious processes of evolution will bring the result. The other class is
composed of suffragists who know that suffrage is coming, but that it is
a very long way off. ‘Surely not in my time,’ they say. Now, if the
optimistic suffragist could become possessed of the idea that evolution
evolves when the people desire it to do so, and that never-ceasing,, self
sacrificing work is necessary from now on; and if the pessimistic suffra
gist could become imbued with the realization that this is the appointed
time; and if both would don their armor and go forth into the campaign
‘to fight and to die’ for the cause, there would be little question of
success.”
CONSTITUTIONALITY OF ILLINOIS SUFFRAGE
LAW ATTACKED BY LIQUOR INTERESTS
Superior Court Dismisses Suit, But Appeal is Taken to Supreme Court.
A suit questioning the constitutionality of the Illinois woman suffrag'e
law was entered in the Superior Court of Cook County on December 10.
Attorneys Levy Mayer and Alfred S. Austrian—who have often been
employed as counsel by the liquor interests—brought suit in the name of
William J. Scown, a contractor, who denied that his case had any con
nection whatever with the saloon interests. Members of the board of
election commissioners are made defendants in the suit, which demands
that an injunction be issued to prevent the board from buying separate
ballot boxes and ballots for the new women voters. The restraining
order also is asked to prevent women participating in the questions of
public policy to be passed upon at the next election—which includes the
saloon issue in many districts. The grounds on which the appellant’s
case is based were summarized in the press as follows:
(1) That permitting women to vote in Illinois will cause an ex
penditure of $200,000 for extra judges and clerks of election, and $60,000
for ballot boxes and ballots.
(2) That the equal suffrage act is a direct violation of Section 7
of the State constitution.
(3) That the granting of the right of women to vote on special
questions to come up at the 1914 elections is a violation of the constitu
tion.
(4) That the naming of specific officers for which women may vote,
as is done in the act, is unconstitutional.
(5) That the suffrage act does not specifically name the bill or bills
that it is intended to amend.
After hearing brief arguments on the 13th Judge Foell of the Superior
Court sustained the demurrer of the defendant and dismissed the suit,
that is, judged the law constitutional. Appeal was immediately taken to
the State Supreme Court, and final decision is predicted for February,
diaries S. Cutting and John J. Herrick have been retained by the suf
fragists to assist the regular attorney for the election board in defend
ing the law.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060379/1914-01-24/ed-1/?sp=4&q=womens+suffrage&st=image&r=-0.299,-0.08,1.599,1.599,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>In her speech at the opening of Parliament the Queen announced
that among other electoral changes the barrier to granting the suffrage
to women contained in the words “male subjects” as a qualification for
voting was to be abolished. The Dutch suffragists consider this was
good news, but vague, as no time was mentioned. They therefore held
a demonstration in front of the House of Parliament, each woman wear
ing a sash with the words “Constitutional Equality for Men and
Women” upon it.
Two Women to Vote at Tokyo Elections.
From The Neiv Statesman comes interesting news of women’s suf
frage in Japan. We learn that the new Government regulation for mu
nicipal elections provides that any person who pays in direct municipal
taxation more than the amount paid by any of the three highest tax
payers of the place shall, even though not ordinarily qualified to be a
citizen, be entitled to vote. We learn also that in Tokyo there are two
women who fulfill these conditions, and unless they are disfranchised
solely on account of their sex, these women should be entitled to vote
at the Tokyo elections.
Suffragists Represented in Toronto Parade and Exhibits.
Suffragists were represented, for the first time, in a recent parade
in Toronto. Their carriage was given a place of honor in the procession,
after the city council. It was decorated profusely in the suffrage colors,
with many flags and yellow bunting, edged with maple leaves—the badge
of Canada. Pligh above the driver was a banner which proclaimed that
“Toronto women want to be citizens.” The carriage was cheered all
HELP THE CAUSE.—Mention the Maryland Suffrage News When Patronizing Our Advertisers.
MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
along the route. We learn that a few militant antis threw acorns, burrs
and sticks of celery at the suffragists, who kept these souvenirs care
fully, saying: “From acorns great oaks grow, and so will the Cause of
Women’s Suffrage from its small beginning. Burrs hold fast, and so
will women workers. Celery purifies the blood, and so will women's
suffrage purify the State —splendid symbols of the movement —all of
them!”
Another suffrage procession, the first of its kind, was recently held
at Port Arthur, Ontario. The cars and carriages, which were gaily
decorated, met with a hearty reception from the crowds. Open-air
speeches were made by Canadian Suffragists.
The suffrage exhibits at the Central Canada Fair, Ottawa, were a
source of great interest to the public, who bought large quantities of
literature, and gladly appended their signatures to a petition to the On
tario Legislature. The suffrage booth looked very gay and attracted
much attention, with its decorations of yellow and purple—the colors of
the Ottawa Equal Suffrage Association; there was also an excellent
display of posters.
Dr. Lillian Smith Vice-President of American Medical Association.
For the first time in its history the American Medical Association
has elected a woman vice-president. Doctor Lillian Smith has done
brilliant work in medical research, especially on the hookworm. In
recording the appointment, The Chicago Record-Herald says: “It is
gratifying to know that the Illinois delegation to the Minneapolis Con
vention is to be credited with the nomination and election of the first
woman vice-president of the association. The Illinois Suffrage Act
figured in the oratory that won.”</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042354/1913-10-24/ed-1/?sp=15&q=womens+suffrage</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>English Non-Militants Keep
Up Fight For Suffrage
LONDON, Oct 24.—The sensational
activities of the militant suffragettes
In recent months have served to ob
Hcure to a considerable degree the
solid, substantial, and really effective
campaign work being done In England
by the large and growing army of
non-militant advocates of votes for j
women. In view of Mrs. Pankhurst's
visit to America, and In order that
American me as well as women may
have an opportunity to make Intelli
gent comparison between the policies,
nethods and aims of the two antag
onistic camps. Mrs. Millicent G. Faw
;ott, leader of the non-militants, has
jrepared for the United Press the
ollowing article:
BV MRS. M. fi, FAWCETT* LL. I).
President of the National Union of
Women's Suffrage Societies.
(Written for the United Press.)
The National Union of Women's Suf
!rage Societies Is the largest, the old
;st. and ns we believe, the best or
/anlzed suffrage society in the United
Kingdom. It Is non- party in char
acter. In the sense that it welcomes
among Its members sympathizers
wlth all political parties or with none,
It Is. and alwavs has been, strict in
Its methods of 'work. The non-mill
tant character of the National Union
Is a matter not only of expediency
bv also of principle:
'We believe that the best method of
promoting the success of our.cause Isj
to appeal to what is the highest andi
best in man. and not to what is
worst; to arouse his sympathy, hisi
conscience, his sense of justice and
his courage, aud not his terror and
cowardice. We contend that all the
women's victories ot the past 50 years!
hpve been won on these lines. Worn-!
en have by peaceful means, by educa-j
lion, by appeals to experience and
common sense, broken down the bar -1
tiers which a generation or two ago
shut out their sex from higher educa -1
:lon. the professionals, municipal
»nd local franchises, employment
ihe Civil Service, etc. The enormous
progress of the women's movement
ias been unstained by crime, or vio
jnce of any kind.
Moreover, in those countries and
itates where full parliamentary suf-1
!rage has been .won It has been won
as the result of peaceful propaganda.
I need only mention the countries!
which have already enfranchised
:heir women. New Zealand. Austra-j
da, Norway. Finland, ten states in
:he United States and the territory of
Alaska. In not one of/4hese has tl\e
women's victory been achieved by
rtolenee. Women's suffrage has pass
5d Its preliminary stages In Den
nark, Sweden, Ireland, and a govern
tnent franchise bill to which women's
Aufträge may be added by amendment,
las recently been mentioned in the
Queen's speech in opening a new
'arliament in Holland. In none of
hese countries has there been the
Elat Meat
4.

Just as Often
i
In spite of soaring prices, Americans like
meat too well to do without it altogether.
And when you can make one pound go as
far as two, and have dishes equally nourish
ing and even more appetizing, you can have meat as often as
you like. The handy 5c and 10c packages of
fioWuA pSwi t&ndJLb,
FOULDSÀ MACARONI
CLEANLY MADE BY AMERICANS
are first aid to the housewife who Is trying to keep down expenses without
lowering her standard of living. It Is the heartiest of all wheat foods, and with
enough meat, or cheese or tomatoes to give the flavor you like best, it makes
dozens of dishes you will be glad to add to your regular bill of fare.
Here are two recipes that ought to be tried right soon. These dishes are
meat, potatoes and vegetable all In one—a full meakjn themselves.
Chipped Beef with Macaroni
Use one five-cent padtage ot Fould»'
Macaroni and one-fourth pound of wafer
sliced dried beef for three or four persons.
Without breaking the sticks, boil and drain
the macaroni as directed In the package.
Shred the dried beef finely and bring to
boil in two cupslul of rich milk; thicken
with flour or com starch stirred np In a
little cold water, remove from the fire and
stir In one well-beaten egg. Put the maca
roni In a serving dish, pout the creamed
mixture over it and sprinkle paprika liter
alfy on top.
These redpes are from The Americanized Macaroni
arsd Spaghetti Cook Book which contains fifty more
some simple, others elaborate enough for any occasion,
all Inexpensive. You owe it to your family and your
purse to leam how to use Foulds to the best advantage.
Send for the Cook Book. It's free.
Hamburger Steak and Spaghetti
Let simmer together for thirty minutes,
half pound hamburger steak, half can to
matoes and half an onion cut fine.
While this Is being done, boll, without
breaking sticks, and drain a five cent rack
f Fonlds'
Spaghetti a directed in the
age o
package.
To the hamburger steak, tomatoes, ctG,
add half pound cheese cut fine or grated,
haJf tablespoon of butter and allow to sim
mer fifteen minutes longer, then add spa
ghetti or arrange spaghetti around the edge
of a warmed meat platter and pour ham
burger steak, tomatoes, etc. In center.
R
So meats, far
Small Families
The Foulds Milling Co.
Chicago, IIL
IO« nga- fw
Large Families
Sales Dept,
Scott's Millinery Shop
$100
Satin Sailors.
Velvet Sailors.
Whips,
Fine Line ol Velvets,
Trimmed or Untrimmed Hats.
I
1
1.35

39c, 49c, 59c. 69c
69c
MABEL B. SCOTT,
614 KINO STREET
THE NEW CASTLE COUNTY MUTUAL
INSURANCE COMPANY announces the
removal pf its Offices from No. 602 Market
Street to No. 1011 Market Street, duPont
Building
least trace of organized or unorgan
ized violence on the part of the advo
cates of the cause.
In Great Britain we have a large num
ber of suffrage societies, represent
ing policies, parties, religious persua
sions, professions and industry, and
among all of these violence as a meth.
od of propaganda has been monop
olized by two societies In England
and one In Ireland. The National Un
ion. which has developed from small
beginnings, nearly half a century ago.
Is not only the largest of all these
organizations but one of the most
democratic institutions In the Uni
ted Kingdom. Every society is en
titled to send delegates, in proportion
to its membership, to the General
Council, which meets twice a year to
decide questions of policy and to elect
officers of the Union.
Our methods of work are entirely
constitutional. We endeavor to edu
cate the*country to sympathy with our
cause by holding meetings, canvass
1°*. conducting press campaigns, and
organizing courses of educational
lectures. Side by sid\w|th our cdu
cational campaign we carry on the
Political side Of our work. Our en
deavor is transform the sympathy
°f the voters Into political pressure
exerted on individual members of par
llaroent, and on parties. In order to
I maintain and Increase a majority in
the House of Commons that is coni
ml tted permanently to the principle
j J* womens suffrage and that will
e dependable iu divisions on the sub
1 ec The latest count gives our num
ber6 aB 43 000 annually subscribing
i members, distributed among our 449
soclties. In addition to these we have
an auxiliary of non-subscribing but
Paused 'Friends of Women Suffrage"
i *0,000 strong- a force created out of
an adaptation of the American plan of
1 en J'P, n f sympathizers,
*t ad no been for the tremen
1 douB activity and ceaseless r dura
Ini*™™ wor h carried on by the non
j militant suffrage societies in the Unl
ted Kingdom, I believe that our move
ment would have been ruined, at any
1 r ate for a generation or more, by rall
j 'fancy.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
